<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog</id>
    <title>Carly.cool Blog</title>
    <updated>2024-06-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Carly.cool Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://coolcarly.github.io/img/my-icon-favicon.ico</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exploration of bread making]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2024/May/bread</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2024/May/bread"/>
        <updated>2024-06-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What I will cover in this post?]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-i-will-cover-in-this-post">What I will cover in this post?<a href="#what-i-will-cover-in-this-post" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What I will cover in this post?" title="Direct link to What I will cover in this post?">​</a></h2><p>In this post, I will talk briefly about the science of bread, go through the optimisation of a bread recipe, testing several parameters including yeast content, hydration and the impact of freezing the dough before cooking. I will end this post by investigating wheat-based composites (basically mixtures of various wheat and non-wheat based flours).</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="a-bit-of-science-behind-bread">A bit of science behind bread<a href="#a-bit-of-science-behind-bread" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to A bit of science behind bread" title="Direct link to A bit of science behind bread">​</a></h2><p><em>9.5.2024</em> <br></p><p>Flour contains proteins glutenin and gliadin, which are hydrophobic (water-hating) peptides. In the presence of water, they will self-assemble to form gluten (Fig 1), which is a result of the molecule preventing the hydrophobic regions from interacting with water. Prior to the addition of water, glutenin exists as a colloid. Upon addition of water to the flour, the chains are allowed to stretch, seperate, and form new disulfide linkages. These disulfide linkages create a network of glutenin polymer that produces the strength and elasticity of bread dough. At the same time, the smaller gliadin proteins will disperse through the glutenin polymer network, which allows the bread to "rise". It is the constituent that facilitates formation of the gluten network. Due to it's self-assembling properties (as it is highly hydrophobic), it will associate into spherical particles and absorb other nutrients such as vitamin E. Thus, the quality of the gluten network that forms is dependent on the type of flour that is used.</p><table><thead><tr><th align="center"><img loading="lazy" alt="Schematic of gluten formation" src="/assets/images/bread_schematic-2d7f68f1f1f8c5e36c0a766763aedc22.jpeg" width="1280" height="453" class="img_ev3q"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="center"><em>Fig 1. Schematic of gluten formation</em></td></tr></tbody></table><p>Mixing and kneading of the flour/water mixture encourages the gluten network to further develop. During this process, carbon dioxide is incorporated, producing a more porous dough once it is baked. Yet, we dont want the gluten networks to be so strong that they become chewy and tough. This is the reason that people turn to a "no-knead" method. Sometimes, a high water content is enough to facilitate formation of strong gluten networks. </p><p>Yet, there is one more ingredient that is required to create the gluten network... and that is salt. As mentioned in the <a href="/science/salt">"salting-out"</a> post, salt helps to decrease the water content. In this instance, salt will remove water from the protein/polymer network to increase the strength and elasicity. </p><hr><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="making-the-initial-loaf">Making the initial loaf<a href="#making-the-initial-loaf" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Making the initial loaf" title="Direct link to Making the initial loaf">​</a></h2><p>The initial recipe that I started with came from Nagi: <a href="https://www.recipetineats.com/easy-yeast-bread-recipe-no-knead/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">RecipeTinEats</a>. The ingredients required were:</p><p align="center"> 450 g flour <br> 2 tsp yeast <br> 2 tsp salt <br> 375 mL of warm watern (~40 °C) </p><p>First, I started off with a "no kneading" approach to bread making. I was unsure of the measurements for the yeast. I had the large container of active yeast as well as the packets. I initially used the packets, and with a quick google search I saw that 7 g was an equivalent of 2 tsp of yeast. Therefore, in my first attempt to make this bread, I activated one packet of the yeast in warm water. The bread was left for a few hours in a warm-ish environment to rise, and then it was moulded into a round ball and baked using the dutch oven.</p><p>After baking, the bread was very tough to cut and very dense, but it was still quite tasty and full of flavour. These bread flavours arise from fermentation. The high density is possibly attributed to a low water content. Thus, for the subsequent loaves, I went for weighing out the ingredients using a scale instead of the "cups" measurement as a scale is more accurate. </p><p>A few days later, I used the recommended amount of yeast (2 tsp), weighed out the flour (450 g to be exact) and the water. I saw that the dough was still a bit "doughy", so I added an extra 20 mL of water to the batch (395 mL in total). It was too sticky to be able to knead (Fig 2, img1), yet it felt very soft and after allowing it to rise for several hours, I baked it using the dutch oven. NOTE: I was sure that it had risen well, when the dough (before baking) was very bubbly on the surface and small movements of the bowl containing the dough resulted in a "jiggling" of the dough surface. This time, it rose more than the previous batch (likely due to the extra yeast) and was less dense than the last batch (owing to the excess water added).</p><table><thead><tr><th align="center"><img loading="lazy" alt="second batch" src="/assets/images/bread2-19d89ba343b4abe8ec1492f13ad64569.jpeg" width="1280" height="416" class="img_ev3q"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="center"><em>Fig 2. Batch 2: (img 1) sticky dough, (img 2) moulded dough for baking, (img 3) final product.</em></td></tr></tbody></table><p>Without a job at this point, I wanted to bake more and change the conditions to geet the best loaf. I wondered what is the impact of leaving the dough to sit for longer? What is the impact of kneading? Surely I can google this, but I wanted to experience the feeling and taste differences. Therefore, the next batch that I made, was using the same contents as above only, I allowed the dough to sit for 3 hours at room temperature, then 2 days in the fridge (covered). The day before cooking, I pulled out the dough, moulded it into a ball and allowed it to sit covered in plastic wrap in the fridge overnight. When I baked this loaf, it rose slightly more than the last batch, and was also more porous (Fig 3). From what I understand, it seems that when you put the dough in the fridge, fermentation is slowed down to allow the development of more complex flavours.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="optimising-a-few-conditions">Optimising a few conditions<a href="#optimising-a-few-conditions" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Optimising a few conditions" title="Direct link to Optimising a few conditions">​</a></h2><table><thead><tr><th align="center"><img loading="lazy" alt="third batch" src="/assets/images/bread-3-688d4025dcac098afd75278bf7cd9fd2.jpeg" width="1280" height="637" class="img_ev3q"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="center"><em>Fig 3. Batch 3: (img 1) moulded dough for baking, (img 2) final product and (img 3) a photo of the sliced bread, observing the porosity of the loaf.</em></td></tr></tbody></table><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="1552024-"><em>15.5.2024</em> <br><a href="#1552024-" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 1552024-" title="Direct link to 1552024-">​</a></h3><p>The next parameter that I wanted to test is the impact of kneading on the dough. Therefore, a dough was prepared as previous, however, it was kneaded for 5 minutes of before allowing the dough to rise. Due to the better properties of the previous batch of bread, the dough was immediately placed in the fridge, in a covered bowel. The dough was left for close to 22 hours in the fridge. The dough appeared to have similar textures as the previous batch, however, was less soft upon touching it.</p><p>The dough was moulded and scored (using tips that I got from <a href="https://vegpatchkitchen.co.uk/what-is-oven-spring/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">vegpatchkitchen</a>) and baked from it's cold state. The idea behind scoring is that it allows the gases to uniformly escape, making bread the rise more uniform, instead of having that weird bubble in the middle of the loaf (as seen in img 2 of Fig 3).</p><p>While the final bread loaf in Fig 4 (img 3) appears to be more uniform, without the ugly bubble in the middle, it was less porous than batch 3 (Fig 3). This was attributed to the small additions of flour that I added in order to knead the bread. As small amounts of excess flour decreases the water content, the bread ultimately became more dense. I thought this bread was the tastiest and best looking so far. </p><table><thead><tr><th align="center"><img loading="lazy" alt="fourth batch" src="/assets/images/bread4-c1294227c25e4d5f5ce68565394cd866.jpeg" width="1280" height="427" class="img_ev3q"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="center"><em>Fig 4. Batch 4: (img 1) dough after kneading and ready to be placed in the frige, (img 2) moulded dough for baking, (img 3) final product and (img 4) a photo of the sliced bread, observing the porosity of the loaf.</em></td></tr></tbody></table><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="2052024-"><em>20.5.2024</em> <br><a href="#2052024-" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 2052024-" title="Direct link to 2052024-">​</a></h3><p>This time, I doubled the batch size using the following ingredients:</p><p align="center"> 900 g bread flour <br> 656 g warm water (~ 40°C) <br> 4 tsp salt <br> 4 tsp of yeast</p><p>In this batch, the process was as follows. First, 4 tsp of dried yeast was added to 2 cups of warm water (equivalent to 427 g of water). The yeast was allowed to grow for 5 minutes and then added to the flour/salt mixture. The mixture was combined with a wooden spoon. As it appeared to be very flaky and floury, an extra 229 g of water was added. It appeared to be very slicky and slimy. It was too sticky to be kneaded, or even handled. This large batch was left in the mixing bowl, covered and put straight into the fridge for 22 hours. </p><p>The oven was preheated to 220°C and the dutch oven was preheated for 30 minutes. During this time, half of the mixture was taken from the large mixing bowl, moulded and scored and put back in the fridge (covered) until it was ready to bake it. The dough (on the baking paper) was gently placed into the dutch oven and baked for 30 mins with the lid on, and a further 10 mins with the lid off. </p><p>The bread was probably the best that I have made so far (I know I say this everytime... but is true). The defining features were the high porosity caused by the high water content, the uniform growth in the dough due to scoring of the loaf and the softness of the inside! </p><table><thead><tr><th align="center"><img loading="lazy" alt="fifth batch" src="/assets/images/bread5-2f25c7674ba79a4c29f3031a018b639a.jpeg" width="1280" height="429" class="img_ev3q"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="center"><em>Fig 5. Batch 5. (img 1) risen dough, (img 2) scored dough, (img 3) baked bread out of the oven and (img 4) image of the face of the bread, showing a higher level of porosity.</em></td></tr></tbody></table><p>The second half of the mixture was left in the fridge for 2 more days. When I removed it from the fridge (22.5.24), the dough revealed bubbles which is indicative of gas being released. It was very sticky and very difficuit to pick up. I managed to mould it into a ball, with the aid of a small amount of flour. The dough was then wrapped in plastic wrap and placed in the freezer, where it sits until I am ready to bake again. Unfortunately due to my new working commitments, I get less time to bake! I will probably bake this loaf next week. Stay tuned!</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="30524"><em>30.5.24</em><a href="#30524" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 30524" title="Direct link to 30524">​</a></h3><p>Yesterday morning, I took the bread dough out of the freezer and placed it ontop of a plastic board, with the plastic wrap still covering it. I allowed it to sit in the fridge while it defrosted. The appearance was no different to when I put it in the freezer, however, it seemed to have less structural integrity (i.e. everytime I tried to mould it into a ball, overtime it would loss the shape). At 4.30pm, I begun preparing the oven to bake the dough. I popped it in for another half an hour bake, followed by 15 minutes without the lid.</p><p>When I pulled it out of the oven, it had a very large circumference which is consistent with the dough losing its shape. It rose a bit, but was not as inflated as previous. I suspect that some of the yeast died when it was frozen and to compensate for this, I shouldve added extra yeast to the batch. The bread was hard on the outside and soft on the inside, just like I like it. It was very porous and tasted good. I think this bread was great overall. </p><table><thead><tr><th align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/bread-20240530-a16ee25a5d1ae99111d0ec6ca8cb3d77.svg" width="2406" height="784" class="img_ev3q"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="center"><em>Fig 6. Batch 6: after the dough was frozen for 1 week, it was defrosted for 2 days in the fridge and then baked as usual.</em></td></tr></tbody></table><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="making-dough-with-the-intention-of-freezing-it">Making dough with the intention of freezing it...<a href="#making-dough-with-the-intention-of-freezing-it" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Making dough with the intention of freezing it..." title="Direct link to Making dough with the intention of freezing it...">​</a></h2><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="162024-"><em>1.6.2024</em> <br><a href="#162024-" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 162024-" title="Direct link to 162024-">​</a></h3><p>In preparation of a new dough, I used the following ingredients: </p><div align="center">451 g flour<br> 3 tsp yeast <br> 1.5 cups of water + extra 48 g <br>1 pinch sugar <br> 2 tsp salt </div><p>In this recipe, I used extra yeast as I intend to freeze the bread. In the <a href="/blog/2024/May/bread#30524">last batch</a>, the bread was really flat and seemed to keep losing it's shape. I attributed the poor shape to yeast dying during the freezing process. This enticed me to use more yeast this time, as I plan to freeze it. </p><p><em>Method</em>
To the yeast, add the warm water and a pinch of sugar. Wait 5-10 minutes for the yeast to foam (I love this part! It's like I am controlling my own little world). Add all dry ingredients to a bowl. Mix around and add the water/yeast mixture. Stir through. (Note: the mixture will be very wet. That is great. The more wet or sticky it is, the more porous it will be! Although I'm not sure how freezing will affect this though) and cover for 3 hours. (Note: I put my dough in the microwave, seems to be a warm spot). </p><p>After 3 hours, I pulled the dough out of the bowl, a lightly covered with flour, being careful not to press it (i.e. knead) too much. Next, I placed it in a bread bag, allowing a little bit of air in and room for the dough to still grow and then put into the freezer where it will sit for a few days. I plan to bake it sometime next week. </p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="1462024-"><em>14.6.2024</em> <br><a href="#1462024-" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 1462024-" title="Direct link to 1462024-">​</a></h3><p>On Tuesday 11.6.24, I pulled the dough out of the freezer and let it defrost in the fridge for 48 hours. On Thursday 13.6.24, when I arrived home from work, I moulded the bread (using some new bread moulders that I got last week) and baked in a preheated dutch oven. The bread was very tasty, with an even amount of pores. It rose a significant amount, indicating that the yeast was still active. The bread remained soft and fresh tasting for 3 days. I will definitely use this freezing method from now on. </p><p>The next task that I will undertake is crafting sourdough bread. I will begin with making a sourdough startup. </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="incorporating-soy-flour">Incorporating Soy Flour<a href="#incorporating-soy-flour" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Incorporating Soy Flour" title="Direct link to Incorporating Soy Flour">​</a></h2><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="22624"><em>22.6.24</em><a href="#22624" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 22624" title="Direct link to 22624">​</a></h3><p>I was in the process of growing my sourdough starter, when I had an urge to bake more bread. This post is exhausted with the optimisation of bread, which I did not want to add to as it would get repetitive overtime. But this loaf was a little different. </p><p>On Thursday evening (20/6/24), I started to foam the yeast in warm water, and weigh out all the ingredients, when I found that we had no flour left. I used 300 g of plain flour. Then I scummaged the cupboard for anything that we may have and I found soy and coconut flour. After doing a quick search online, I found that people often add soy flour to their recipe to create softer bread. The highest % of soy flour incorporated was 10%. Therefore, I changed the recipe and used soy flour with plain flour. In my recipe, I used 16% of soy flour.</p><p><strong>Ingredients:</strong></p><div align="center"> 300 g plain flour <br> 50 g soy flour <br> 295 g water <br> 2 tsp yeast <br> 1 tsp salt <br> a little flour for working up the dough <br> </div><p><strong>Steps:</strong></p><ol><li>As usual, the yeast was grown in the warm water until it foamed (5 mins). </li><li>Dry ingredients were combined</li><li>Everything was mixed with a wooden spoon. The dough was very sticky and hydrated!</li><li>The mixing bowl was covered and left and placed in the fridge for 36 hours. (note: by putting it in the fridge it slows the fermentation process. I think it was perfect at about 24 hours.)</li><li>The dutch oven was preheated to 220 °C for 30 minutes</li><li>The dough was taken from the fridge and folded a few times (with a little bit of spared flour for working). I believe this is a crucial step to ensure that the bread is porous but not too porous. </li><li>The dough was placed in the dutch oven (using baking paper to transfer) and cooked for 30 minutes with the lid on, then 10 minutes with the lid off. </li><li>The bread was allowed to cool for 10 minutes before we had it for breakfast! 😊</li></ol><p>The bread was so soft! Unlike the other loaves that I made, this one was very easy to cut through. It was so soft in the mouth and had a different flavour to it. I'm not sure if the flavour was because there was a lower flour to yeast ratio, or due to the Soy flour, but it was definitely tasty and slightly sweeter than usual. It should also be noted that previous studies with soy flour have indicated that 10% incorporation is best for the texture and flavour of bread. </p><table><thead><tr><th align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/bread6-fef781444b4ed95da22d6da3ee6d0fe2.jpeg" width="1280" height="356" class="img_ev3q"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="center"><em>Img caption: Bread made with 16% soy flour</em></td></tr></tbody></table><p>As you can see from the images, the crumb of soy flour is slightly browner than previous loaves, with the crust being more golden. Soy bean itself is hydrophillic (water-loving) compared to wheat-flour which is water-hating. In bread recipes using 100% wheat flour, the hydrophobic associations (forms of non-covalent bonds, or interactions between molecules) between the gluten network make the bread quite tough. On the other hand, as soy flour is hydrophillic, it is more effective at absorbing water, which means that by incorporating soy flour into the dough, you will retain a higher level of water during the baking process. The proteins in soy will interact with water, and as the water evaporates, the bonds are less tough and therefore the bread will be softer.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="references">References<a href="#references" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to References" title="Direct link to References">​</a></h2><ol><li>Cho, I.H. and D.G. Peterson, Chemistry of bread aroma: A review. Food Science and Biotechnology, 2010. 19(3): p. 575-582.</li><li>Sha, X., et al., The prolamins, fro structure, property, to the function in encapsulation and delivery of bioactive compounds. Food Hydrocolloids, 2024. 149: p. 109508.</li><li>Taghdir M, Mazloomi SM, Honar N, Sepandi M, Ashourpour M, Salehi M. Effect of soy flour on nutritional, physicochemical, and sensory characteristics of gluten-free bread. Food Sci Nutr. 2017; 5: 439–445. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/fsn3.411" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://doi.org/10.1002/fsn3.411</a></li></ol>]]></content>
        <category label="baking" term="baking"/>
        <category label="bread" term="bread"/>
        <category label="my vegetarian cookbook" term="my vegetarian cookbook"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PhD examination]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2024/05/28/2024/May/</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2024/05/28/2024/May/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[*Date created: 28.05.24,]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Date created: 28.05.24,
Date modified: 17.06.24</em> </p><p><em>Date: 28.05.24</em> <br>
What's new in the life of Carly? Recently I started working as a laboratory technician for ANFF (<a href="https://anff.org.au" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Australian National Fabrication Facility</a>), back at the Innovation Campus in Wollongong. ANFF is a government funded organisation that is designed to support Research and Development. There are several nodes located around Australia, with several in each state. The ANFF Materials node is located here at the University of Wollongong as well as the University of Newcastle, specialising in polymers, bioinks, and electromaterials.</p><p>I have been here for 2 weeks so far. At the moment, the work is pretty slow, yet I am trying to keep busy. I have been trained on the <a href="/blog/2024/May/icp_">ICP</a> and elemental analyser and am waiting for traiing by Greg on the digestor in order to further my training on the ICP. I hope to use it a few times in order to become more familiar since I am now the official trainer for it. While I wait for things to happen here, I have continued my learning with python. In fact, today I wrote a program with the following purposes: </p><ol><li>To create a new folder with the month, then a folder with the date</li><li>To take a file and convert it from txt to csv</li><li>To extract the X and Y values from the folder and normalise the Y column. </li><li>To create a line graph of the X and normalised Y values. </li><li>To export the image as a png with the date and activity as the file name. </li></ol><p>I feel as excited about programing as I did with the synthesis of my polymers. Both of these skills have different thresholds and I think they can complement each other very nicely. I just wish I could get a mixture of lab work and desk work... As I was told today "This place is very slow, as there are many changes happening.."</p><p>In addition, I have been learning a bi¬t of LaTeX. It was a large hurdle and a little traumatic installing it, only for Nick to point out to me later on that Typst (which I am more fluent with) is open access for offline use (something I did not realise before). Therefore, I looked through the extensions of VSCode and found the typst extension, which I immediately installed. I began to create a template for my publications, which is much nicer than using microsoft word!!!! If I could do one thing over again, it would be to use typst for my thesis. I will definitely be using this to create reports in the future. </p><p>In other news, both of the examiners have returned my PhD thesis. I am yet to receive it, however, my supervisors have told me that there are mostly minor corrections (They didn't want to give me too much information, and later I learned that they are not allowed to tell me anything). I'm hoping that I can correct it soon, but I am very nervous about what it will say! </p><div align="center"><table><thead><tr><th align="center"><img loading="lazy" alt="phd revision" src="/assets/images/phd-revision-2c8dffaf22a0504d3a2f184d98aba560.PNG" width="517" height="265" class="img_ev3q"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="center"><em>Caption: The only information I can get about my thesis at this point</em></td></tr></tbody></table></div><p><em>Date: 13.06.24</em> <br>
On Friday, 7 June 2024 at 8:57 AM, I received an email from the Graduate Research School with my thesis examination. My PhD will be awarded, pending minor changes to the thesis. This is probably the best result that I could hope for.</p><p>As I read the examiners reports, I was at first shocked and overwhelmed by the reports, however, as I read on, I realised that it was very positive, with only grammatical errors and mistakes. I ended up fixing my thesis within a day. </p><p>One of my reviewers said "The number of experiments performed was really impressive, even if part of them were unsuccessful and did not lead to the desired product." The other said "In summary, this is an excellent thesis and I recommend that the candidate be awarded a PhD degree." This made me feel really good about it. While I didn't get a commended thesis, I am glad that the reviews were positive. </p><p><em>Date: 17.06.24</em> <br>
On Thursday 13 June 2024, I met with my PhD supervisors and discussed my thesis. They were happy with the changes that I made and gave me a few additional suggestions. The next day, I sent an email to the head of postgraduate studies asking if he was happy with my corrections. After consulting with my supervisors, he then sent an email to the graduate research school approving my final submission. At 10:15 am today, I submitted the final version of my thesis!!! I am proud of the work I did and while I haven't published any manuscripts (yet hopefully), I believe I added something novel to the literature.</p>]]></content>
        <category label="PhD" term="PhD"/>
        <category label="work" term="work"/>
        <category label="thesis corrections" term="thesis corrections"/>
        <category label="python" term="python"/>
        <category label="programming" term="programming"/>
        <category label="LaTeX" term="LaTeX"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Preparing tempeh]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2024/June/tempeh</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2024/June/tempeh"/>
        <updated>2024-06-16T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For dinner tonight, I wanted to prepare a couple of Greek Gyros, inspired by Recipetineats. Tofu was an option to use as the main protein content, however, tofu is very soft and wouldn't go well with a wrap of this sort (to my opinion). Therefore, tempeh was the next best thing.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For dinner tonight, I wanted to prepare a couple of Greek Gyros, inspired by <a href="https://www.recipetineats.com/greek-chicken-gyros-with-tzatziki/#wprm-recipe-container-21826" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Recipetineats</a>. Tofu was an option to use as the main protein content, however, tofu is very soft and wouldn't go well with a wrap of this sort (to my opinion). Therefore, tempeh was the next best thing.</p><p>Previously, I attempted to cook tempeh, however, it turned out terrible! It is a very tough soy-based protein, so if it is not cooked properly, then it won't be very tasty. </p><p>I read several blogs, saying that you can bake it as is.. Others say you need to steam it. I decided to go with steaming. I did about 20-30 minutes of steaming. Even after 30 minutes, it felt tough! Now I realise that 15 minutes would have been sufficient as later baking makes it softer. </p><p>After steaming the tempeh, it was marinated with oregano (1 tsp), yogurt (2 tbsp), lemon juice (1 tbsp), salt (1 tsp) and pepper (1/4 tsp). I allowed it to soak up the marinate for 1 hour before I baked the tempeh. Usually, I would let the marinade soak for 3 hours min, however, as the tempeh was hot and the proteins somewhat denatured from the steaming, I thought that 1 hour was sufficient enough to allow the tempeh to absorb the flavour.</p><p>The tempeh was placed in an oven proof dish (trying to conserve the marinate in the dish) and baked for 10 minutes at 220 °C, mixed with the excess marinade and then baked for another 10 minutes. </p><p>The tempeh was then used as a chicken substitue in a wrap, with a homemade tzatzkiki and flatbread. </p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eHMIEHjhjxs?si=faVa6XkIVwEvP7TV" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin"></iframe>]]></content>
        <category label="my vegetarian cookbook" term="my vegetarian cookbook"/>
        <category label="cooking" term="cooking"/>
        <category label="tempeh" term="tempeh"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mudgee, NSW 🍷]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2024/June/mudge-24</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2024/June/mudge-24"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the long weekend, Nick and I headed to 📍 Mudgee, NSW, Australia with a group of Nick's friends. We were staying in a cute house in Erudgere (~10 mins from Mudgee centre). It was a large house, with 2 bathrooms (and an ensuite, which was apart of a different bedroom - not ours), which were very modern. The house appeared to be recently renovated. There were 7 bedrooms, each containing double beds. We took the bedroom opposite the kitchen.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the long weekend, Nick and I headed to 📍 <a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/mc1zKcQgysVsQXE17" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Mudgee, NSW, Australia</a> with a group of Nick's friends. We were staying in a cute house in Erudgere (~10 mins from Mudgee centre). It was a large house, with 2 bathrooms (and an ensuite, which was apart of a different bedroom - not ours), which were very modern. The house appeared to be recently renovated. There were 7 bedrooms, each containing double beds. We took the bedroom opposite the kitchen. </p><p>This place had a large backyard with the most incredible spa (we went in every night!!! I cannot resist a large body of water). There was also a fire pit located in the yard (about 25 m from the house). Every night, we sat by the fire. It was pretty great. Over the time that we were here, the temperatures were very cool with a maximum of 14 °C. </p><h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="friday-7-june-2024"><em>Friday 7 June 2024</em><a href="#friday-7-june-2024" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to friday-7-june-2024" title="Direct link to friday-7-june-2024">​</a></h4><p>We drove up on Friday afternoon. We were very lucky that our neighbours were happy to mind Chip and we said that we should gift them some wine as a thankyou. We arrived at 8.30 pm, after a 4 hour long trip, with very little traffic (most traffic through the Blue Mountains). On the drive, I was astounded at how many cars were travelling this far west. I thought to myself that surely they are not all going to Mudgee? Once we passed Lithgow, all the traffic mostly subsided and we drove alone on the roads.</p><h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="saturday-8-june-2024"><em>Saturday 8 June 2024</em><a href="#saturday-8-june-2024" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to saturday-8-june-2024" title="Direct link to saturday-8-june-2024">​</a></h4><p>On the Saturday morning, we headed into town and bought coffee from <em>Althea by Zin.</em> This was a very cute little bakery, which sold artisan bread and other pastry treats. The coffee was pretty good, despite us having to order a double shot, and also considering that it was pretty expensive ($11 for two coffees). </p><p>We returned home by 10 am and at 11 am, Adam (a local wine tour guy) picked us up to take us to and from Robert Steins Vineyard (for $100). We had a 11.30 am wine tasting. The wines were good (not sure how else to comment about them). My favourites were definitely the Dry rose and the 2021 Shiraz. </p><p>Lunch was booked at 12 pm at Pipeclay (the restaurant attached). We sat at a long table booked for 11. Our lunch consisted of a 6 course meal, each meal with a wine pairing, which spanned 3.5 hours! The six courses included: </p><ol><li>Pipeclay Pumphouse Charcuterie: which was basically a cheese/meat board with bread. The bread served was pretty amazing. </li><li>Watercress, shiitake mushrooms, chestnut and poached egg: A green soup which I thought was super tasty! However, the poached eggs were over cooked and very hard, despite the waiter describing that the main feature of the dish was the "soft egg and runny yolk."</li><li>Beef carpaccio with ginger and lemongrass: It looked amazing, however, for me (the vegetarian), they substituted the meat for sweet potato. It was tasty!</li><li>Chinese Five Spice  duck breast with squash, potato and broccolini. This meal was the highlight. The duck alternative was pumpkin. The dish was exactly the same, only the duck was substituted. I noted the flavours of the spice and the milky mash potato underneath. I especially liked the peppery taste of the pumpkin. I would like to try and recreate this dish at some point.</li><li>Strawberry sorbet as the palate cleanser before dessert, which was: </li><li>Spiced coconut custard tart with banana and green tea ice cream. I can't comment too much about it. It was good. Probably as good as a tart can get. </li></ol><table><thead><tr><th align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/mudgee1-a34fcc3c709ebb1aa47caaeb42364f21.jpeg" width="1280" height="868" class="img_ev3q"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="center"><em>Img Caption: Robert Steins six course meal.</em></td></tr></tbody></table><p>While the meals were tasty, I left the restaurant after 3.5 hours still feeling hungry. It is not enough to simply substitute the meat for vegetables. It seemed like it wasn't really considered, and they only cared for creating a similar flavour. In addition, the service was very slow! I felt like I spent my whole day there, and I did!</p><p>The wine pairings were pretty good as well. However, the waiter forgot our last pairing! It really did undermine their services there and I probably would not recommend this place, nor return, considering that we paid $110 per person + $60-80 for the wine pairing. Furthermore, it seemed like the staff constantly forgot about us, with people who arrived hours after us, leaving before us!! </p><p>Just before we got our coffees, the bus driver arrived to pick us up. We ended up taking a takeaway coffee on the bus on the drive back to our accomodation, where we enjoyed a fire and BBQ dinner. </p><p><em>Sunday 9 June 2024</em>
We were up at 7 am, and headed into Mudgee on a coffee run. We drove about 10 minutes to the Dancing Goat, where we ordered 9 coffees (including a coffee for ourselves). </p><p>The Dancing Goat was a cute coffee shop, which seemed to be family owned and run. There were kids under 12 working as the Hostess and the Cashier. We immediately felt bad for our large order, but it didn't matter because they handled it rather well. The coffees came out in under 10 minutes, hand delivered to us in two very stable carry trays. </p><p>After returning back to the house and eating breakfast with coffee, we headed off on a wine tour with Scotty (an employee of Adam). He picked us up at 9.35 am to which we arrived at our first winery for the day: </p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="1-heslop">1. Heslop:<a href="#1-heslop" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 1. Heslop:" title="Direct link to 1. Heslop:">​</a></h3><p>When we arrived (~9.50 am), I was thinking that we would have to wait until they open (usually 10 am?), but they let us start early. As we walked through the front Garden, we arrived at a house. There were two people who greeted us - a woman named Julie, of about 65-70 years and a male of about 40 years of age, named Liam. They were a mother and son duo. They also mentioned that there was another member, Bob (Julie's husband) but he was currently constructing a new wine cellar.  </p><p>They led us into a small cosy room, decorated with a wide variety of wines. Julie was leading the wine tour and she allowed us to try a wide range (7-10 wines) of wines, with 95% of the grapes grown on site (the other 5% were grown as Bunnamagoo). Some wines of interest was the vermentino. We later learned that Vermentino is a grape that is trying to replace the Savignon Blanc (from NZ), as the acidity can be better controlled. The Rose, and Zinfandel were also pretty amazing wines and the best of Mudgee. </p><p>Although, Zinfandel (I knew nothing about this grape variety previously), is a grape grown in California. Liam (the wine maker) spent 1 year abroad in California and fell in love with "Zin" and decided to invest in it. They now are one of a few wineries that grow Zinfandel in Mudgee. </p><p>As we were deciding of the wines to buy, Julie said "If you are saving yourself for the rest of the day because you think they might get better.... let me tell you, they  don't. They are not as good as here." She was right. They were the best wines of the day to which I later (Monday) voted them the best Wine cellar of Mudgee. </p><p>We purchased 3 bottles from Heslop, including 2x Vermentino's and 1x Shiraz. I will put this winery on my list to return to next time I visit Mudgee. </p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="2-bunnamagoo">2. Bunnamagoo:<a href="#2-bunnamagoo" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 2. Bunnamagoo:" title="Direct link to 2. Bunnamagoo:">​</a></h3><p>The next place was <em>Bunnamagoo</em>. It was more of a commercial vineyard, yet it had a really pretty lookout onto the landscape. Most of the white wines I did not enjoy here... Until we got to the reds. The reds were quite enjoyable and we ended up buying a Cabernet Shiraz Merlot and a Shiraz which was so delicious! Funny story though, as we were loading the van with our wines, Nick set off the fire extinguisher. It let out a whole lot of foam, which everyone joked about for the rest of the day. </p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="3-huntington">3. Huntington:<a href="#3-huntington" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 3. Huntington:" title="Direct link to 3. Huntington:">​</a></h3><p><em>Huntington</em> followed. It was also a very pretty vineyard. Lots of bushery and trees still containing their 'autumn leaves.' When we entered the cellar, we were escorted upstairs to a medium sized room, with a long, narrow, wooden table to seat 11. We sat on wooden stools and a tall guy (sorry I do not recall his name) talked us through the wines. Attached to the room was a bathroom. From where I was sitting I could clearly see a bathtub and a shower. Over the bath was a long board and wine bottles stacked atop. It seemed like it was an old converted house where they did wine tastings. </p><p>The wines here were nicer than Bunnamagoo (in my opinion). Some noteworthy wines were the Chardonnay which I finally realised, has a certain butteriness to it. I had heard people comment about the butteriness of Chardonnays but I never really tasted it or realised this taste until now! All the reds were again very nice, and we ended up buying a Shiraz Cabernet. </p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="4-moothi-estate">4. Moothi Estate<a href="#4-moothi-estate" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 4. Moothi Estate" title="Direct link to 4. Moothi Estate">​</a></h3><p>The next place we showed up at was <em>Moothi Estate.</em> It was meant to be for lunch, but the only thing on their menu were cheese boards and fries. Their service was also very slow. Later I was informed that it was shutting down the next day.&nbsp;Nevertheless, this place was not memorable for me. </p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="5-craigmoor-and-burnbrae-vineyards">5. Craigmoor and Burnbrae Vineyards<a href="#5-craigmoor-and-burnbrae-vineyards" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 5. Craigmoor and Burnbrae Vineyards" title="Direct link to 5. Craigmoor and Burnbrae Vineyards">​</a></h3><p>We went to a few more places after this, including <em>Craigmoor</em> and <em>Burnbrae Vineyards</em>. There was nothing really memorable about these places. For one thing, the staff at Craigmoor were very distracted, and did not explain much of the wines. This is most likely due to everyone getting to choose their own wines and our wine conniseur trying to meet everyones needs. The staff at Burnbrae were very nice, however, by this point we were so tired and I was almost sick with each sip of wine. However, we did buy a bottle from here, as usual, a Shiraz. </p><table><thead><tr><th align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/mudgee2-a33cd78aefa7bb9124c6a9b99a1aeaa1.jpeg" width="1280" height="638" class="img_ev3q"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="center"><em>Img Caption: A few pics of my favourite wineries of the day</em></td></tr></tbody></table><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="some-notes">Some notes<a href="#some-notes" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Some notes" title="Direct link to Some notes">​</a></h3><p>I have a few observatory notes about the wineries and vineyards around Mudgee: </p><ol><li>You will always pay a Wine Tasting fee regardless of the amount of wine that you buy. </li><li>The wines are cheaper than those in the Hunter Valley. </li><li>It is a different vibe, less laid back than the Hunter Valley. </li><li>It was less touristy than the Hunter Valley. </li><li>Maybe a little more "snobby" about the wines here. </li></ol><p>I also want to comment that five wineries in one day is TOO MUCH. I already knew this before hand, but I must stress this here. After the first three, the wines felt like a chore to drink and I enjoyed them far less. It was very annoying that we arrived back so late (close to 5 pm), and I was feeling very stressed that I could not run or do anything else aside from drink wine. </p><h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="monday-10-june-2024"><em>Monday 10 June 2024</em><a href="#monday-10-june-2024" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to monday-10-june-2024" title="Direct link to monday-10-june-2024">​</a></h4><p>We slept in until 8 am. My legs were hurting a little bit, maybe from laying down for so long, or the lack of training over this weekend. We got up, dressed, and cleaned the kitchen from last nights pizza's and then headed into Mudgee for breakfast. </p><p>We were planning to go back to the Dancing Goat, however, when we parked, there were lots of people lined up waiting for a seat and therefore, we decided to go somewhere else. We ended up going to Alby and Esters. It was a cute cafe in a garden. There were street side seating, then once you walked through a short alley way, there was an open garden filled with tables, and two different indoor seating areas. It was a rather large space for dinning in. When we walked in, it was pretty busy but we still managed to get a seat inside. It was noisy inside but since it was pretty cold (under 10 degrees), we decided to stay put. </p><p>We ordered coffees (strong) and breakfast: Poached eggs for me and a jaffle for Nick. It was a nice breakfast. Our meals came with a side of tomato relish which gave the eggs more flavour. The tomato relish was amazing, which we later realised that they made themselves, with jars onsale to the public. I commented about how we should eat tomato relish more often. I noted that I should add it to our breakfast rolls. </p><p>After breakfast, we ordered  another coffee and a lemon + blueberry (gluten free) cake. It was an enjoyable morning and we left the cafe with full bellies. We returned back to the house at 10.30 am but we were straight out of the door again as the gang wanted to go to the Cheese shop. We headed to High Valley Cheese Co. </p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="high-valley-cheese-co">High Valley Cheese Co.<a href="#high-valley-cheese-co" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to High Valley Cheese Co." title="Direct link to High Valley Cheese Co.">​</a></h3><table><thead><tr><th align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/mudgee4-b85a46c9613811ea692404d026934163.jpeg" width="1280" height="462" class="img_ev3q"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="center"><em>Img Caption: Cheese tasting at High Valley Cheese Co.</em></td></tr></tbody></table><p>The High Valley Cheese Co. is located very close to Mudgee town,maybe 5 mins or so. It is clearly visible from the road. It was a rather small shop located on a large property. The shop fit about 10 people at one time (very squashed). The cool thing was that the cheese tastings here were free! This is the only tasting that we have been to thus far that has been free. </p><p>We tried a range of cheeses, from feta to cheddar and blue cheese. They were very tasty. I didn't have much of an appetite when we arrived and so I did not try the Feta. However, I was told that it was delicious and there were many people in the group who bought one of the Feta variations. The other cheeses that we tasted included the Caerphilly, Smoked Cheddar, Smoked Chilli cheddar, Brie, Rouge, Stefan Blue and Coil Y Blue. All the cheese were enjoyable aside from the last one. The Coil Y Blue literally tasted like a farm (but I do not enjoy blue cheese). </p><p>As there were 11 people in our group, there was a backlog of people lining up, and the line spanned out a few meters. I later thought to myself that I would hate to stand in that line, because it moved very slowly. But the cheese conniseurs were very good at their job and it was my favourite tasting today!!!</p><p>We ended up buying the Smoky cheddar cheese and the Rouge. The smoky cheddar was so smoky! I loved it the most. The Rouge was a version of brie, slightly younger but also very nice. </p><p>Next stop was Mudgee town so some of the gang could get coffee and then we were off to Bakers &amp; Williams Distillery.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="bakers--williams-distillery">Bakers &amp; Williams Distillery<a href="#bakers--williams-distillery" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Bakers &amp; Williams Distillery" title="Direct link to Bakers &amp; Williams Distillery">​</a></h3><p>Bakers &amp; Williams Distillery was booked for 12 pm at $5 pp. As we walked through a side fence, we walked through a yard with an amazing view of a vineyard. There were several tables set up and lots of flowers around! </p><table><thead><tr><th align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/mudgee3-2a88e9e136777abd62906d0443b5db1f.jpeg" width="1280" height="321" class="img_ev3q"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="center"><em>Img caption: A very pretty distillery 'Bakers &amp; Williams' with a marvelous view of the vineyard and a selection of liqueurs to taste.</em></td></tr></tbody></table><p>We walked into a small garage which was decked out as a tasting room. We tried a variety of Gins and Liqueurs, which we were informed were all made onsite. Even the waxing of the bottles was done onsite.
The tasting list consisted of: </p><ul><li>XLCR Gin: This tasted like a normal Gin to me, and I am not a huge fan, however Nick loved it! </li><li>Shiraz Gin: Was better but still not my style. The taste was improved when mixed with a grapefruit soda. </li><li>#Orancello: This was pretty amazing. Exactly like lemoncello, just with orange. We ended up buying a bottle of this. </li><li>Lemon Myrtle: This was pretty nice as well. </li><li>Cafe Liquor: Also great, tasted like an iced coffee.</li><li>Butterscotch Snapps: SO good! Tasted like butterscotch sauce. </li></ul><p>Despite the group buying a number of liquers, we still had to pay a tasting fee. </p><p>Next, we headed for lunch at Blue Wren.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="blue-wren-farm">Blue Wren Farm<a href="#blue-wren-farm" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Blue Wren Farm" title="Direct link to Blue Wren Farm">​</a></h3><p>Lunch was booked for 1.30 pm, but we showed up to Blue Wren Farm ~40 minutes early. They allowed us to sit. The waiters were very good and accomodated us very well. However, there was not much to eat for vegetarians, so I had bread and potatos for lunch + a lemon lime and bitters. I wasn't too fussed though because I was still full from our large breakfast. It just annoyed me that it costed $40 just for bread and potatos. Once everyone was finished eating, I was pretty keen to leave and do other things with the day. </p><p>The final destination was the Pieter Van Gent Vineyard. </p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="pieter-van-gent-vineyard">Pieter Van Gent Vineyard<a href="#pieter-van-gent-vineyard" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Pieter Van Gent Vineyard" title="Direct link to Pieter Van Gent Vineyard">​</a></h3><p>Pieter Van Gent is located on a large farm. As you enter the drive way there were several lodges and paddicks, seeming to be accomodation for tourists. As we approached the end of the dirt driveway, we found a parking lot to the right of a farmhouse. On the outside of the farmhouse entrance, there was a nice sign advertising that this was a cellar door. The entrace pathway was about 10 m long, with large barrels, of a rusty brown colour on either side. As I walked through the entrance, the floor was covered in grey stone and the lighting was rather dull to give a very cool jazzy farmer vibe. There were a number of tables and chairs which lined the corridor of the long entrance way. We sat in a "U shape" seating, where we were greeted by a wine connoisseur who seemed to know a lot about the wines. </p><table><thead><tr><th align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/mudgee5-6ac6038fec2de454f947a8bdfe47fc76.jpeg" width="1280" height="481" class="img_ev3q"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="center"><em>Img caption: Large wooden barrels that filled the corridor.</em></td></tr></tbody></table><p>Our tasting consisted of five wines ($10 pp/tasting) including a vermentino, moscato, Shiraz, Tawny and a "white port". We learned that this place specialises in Tawny and so many members of our group loved it. Most of the wines here were not my style, however, the 2013 Shiraz was pretty nice and we ended up purchasing a bottle ($20 special, but with tasting fee it costed $30). </p><p>I was glad that we got back before the sunset today, so I could go for quick 5 km run. It made me feel great after a long weekend of drinking wine. Other wineries were suggested to us, which will be on the list for the next time we go, including <a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/kXz5CTgC7jScMVzX6" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Lowe Family Wines</a> and Di Lusso (although, the owners are planning to sell so may not be around for much longer).</p><p>In the evening, we enjoyed another fire. </p><table><thead><tr><th align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/mudgee6-abadba4b52cc4795d8d7873c80c7ca5b.jpeg" width="960" height="1280" class="img_ev3q"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="center"><em>Img Caption: Our evening fire to keep warm in Mudgee</em></td></tr></tbody></table><h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="tuesday-11-june-2024"><em>Tuesday 11 June 2024</em><a href="#tuesday-11-june-2024" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to tuesday-11-june-2024" title="Direct link to tuesday-11-june-2024">​</a></h4><p>We were up at 7 am, cleaning and packing before heading off at 8 am. We stopped at the Dancing Goat Cafe in Mudgee and ordered a coffee and takeaway rolls: a B&amp;E roll for Nick and an Egg roll for me. Note: they weren't so much rolls as they were burgers, and they were pretty great as well. This was my favourite cafe in Mudgee and I would go back here again if we ever come back to Mudgee. </p><p>As we drove in the dark on the way to Mudgee, we did not get to see any of the features such as the rolling hills and the mountenous backdrop. The drive home was pretty great, especially heading through the Blue Mountains. Nick and I spoke about the rolling hills and how how cool they were. In terms of country and land, Mudgee is a lot nicer to look at than the Hunter Valley (in my opinion).</p><p>A 4-hour drive later and we were back in Wollongong.</p><p>Note to self: 5 days is too long to go without running, as my legs felt exhausted after the 5 km run. Now, I am going to start preparing for the Husky marathon in Huskisson in November. 🏃🏽‍♀️🏃🏽‍♀️🏃🏽‍♀️</p>]]></content>
        <category label="Mudgee" term="Mudgee"/>
        <category label="Wine tours" term="Wine tours"/>
        <category label="Wine" term="Wine"/>
        <category label="Vineyards" term="Vineyards"/>
        <category label="Shiraz" term="Shiraz"/>
        <category label="Long weekend" term="Long weekend"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Puff pastry]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2024/June/pastry</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2024/June/pastry"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Preparation of the pastry]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="preparation-of-the-pastry">Preparation of the pastry<a href="#preparation-of-the-pastry" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Preparation of the pastry" title="Direct link to Preparation of the pastry">​</a></h2><p><em>1.6.24</em><br>
From my <a href="/blog/2024/May/spinach_cheese_triangles">previous post</a>, I prepared puff pastry with flour, butter and water. The puff pastry was then used to make spinach and cheese triangles. They were very nice, but the pastry was very sweet. Therefore, I wanted to create a recipe that was less sweet and more to my tastes. To achieve this, I decreased the amount of butter and added oil and extra salt. </p><p>The ingredients were as follows: </p><div align="center"> 400 g plain flour <br> 1 tsp salt <br> 53 g butter <br> 1 tbsp olive oil <br> 155 g water <br> </div><p><em>Method:</em>
In a large mixing bowl, the flour and salt were combined. Butter was chopped into small squares and using my hands, the flour and butter were rubbed together creating a crumbly flour. Next, the oil was added and the flour/butter mixture and oil were gently rubbed together (now, the texture was more crumbly). Finally, I added 155 g water (Note, I weight out the water, but it would equate to 155 mL). and used my hands to mix. The mixture was crumbly, but good enough to roll out. With floured hands and a lightly floured surface, I rolled the dough out into a long, thin pastry (maybe 0.5 cm thick?). Next I folded it several times onto itself and covered in plastic wrap. The covered dough was placed in the fridge.</p><table><thead><tr><th align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/pastry2-9f2e8275824cd100584942f5cd58d64f.jpeg" width="1280" height="383" class="img_ev3q"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="center"><em>Img caption: From preparing the crumbling dough by rubbing ingredients together, to rolling out the dough and folding it into a plastic wrap</em></td></tr></tbody></table><p>I think 2 hours is adequate enough to chill the pastry, however, I left it in the fridge until I wanted to use it. </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="further-preparation">Further preparation<a href="#further-preparation" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Further preparation" title="Direct link to Further preparation">​</a></h2><p><em>2.6.24</em><br>
I pulled the dough out of the fridge and unwrapped it. There were folding marks present, however once I rolled it out with a rolling pin, the dough became smooth again. I tried to roll it out as thin as I could and then cut it into three sections. One filled the inside of a pan, and the other is to act as a pie top (for dinner tomorrow night, see image 1 below). Both were covered and placed in the fridge again. </p><table><thead><tr><th align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/pastry3-8e28a7de5c3324474ce20bb3bc1581a4.jpeg" width="1280" height="554" class="img_ev3q"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="center"><em>Img caption: Preparation of a pie (left) and the cheese triangles after baking (right)</em></td></tr></tbody></table><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="cheese-trianges">Cheese trianges<a href="#cheese-trianges" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Cheese trianges" title="Direct link to Cheese trianges">​</a></h3><p>With the third section, I divided it into five small triangles. 1 tsp of filling was placed in the centre of each triangle and then it was folded onto itself several times to make a triangle like shape. The triangles were placed in the oven to bake for 30 minutes.  </p><p>The filling consisted of: </p><div align="center"> 1/4 cup ricotta <br> 1/4 cup crumbled feta <br>  pinch of nutmeg + pepper <br> 1/4 cup tasty cheese<br> sprinkle of bread crumbs <br> 1 egg <br></div><p>I have to say, I enjoyed this pastry! It tasted very savoury, and you could not pick up any sweetness, only from that of the cheese. </p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="spinach-and-ricotta-pie">Spinach and ricotta pie<a href="#spinach-and-ricotta-pie" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Spinach and ricotta pie" title="Direct link to Spinach and ricotta pie">​</a></h3><p><em>3.6.24</em>
<strong>Ingredients list:</strong></p><div align="center"> 100 g ricotta<br> 50 g crumbled feta<br> 1/2 cup tasty cheese <br> 2 eggs <br> hand full of spinach <br> 1 cup of sliced mushroom <br> 1 tbsp olive oil <br> 1/2 brown onion <br></div><p>When I arrived home from work, around 5 pm, I preheated the oven to 200 degrees. In a frypan, I cooked onion in ~1tbsp of olive oil until it was translucent. Next, the mushrooms were added and fried for about 7 minutes (until brown and sweating), finally I added 2 handfulls of fresh spinach and cooked until wittled. Mixture was cooled for a few minutes.</p><p>The mushroom mixture was added to a bowl filled with ricotta, feta, tasty cheese and egg. The mixture was stirred and then transferred to the baking dish containing the pastry. Next, the second sheet of pastry was placed on top and the edges were joined together using a fork. Holes were marked in the top of the pie using a fork and then the pie was briefly brushed with milk. </p><p>The pie was baked for 40 minutes, and left to sit at room temperature for 10 minutes before eating. </p><table><thead><tr><th align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/pastry-pie-b34656f0b5ba354abaad2636d42be8eb.jpeg" width="476" height="393" class="img_ev3q"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="center"><em>Img Caption: Tonights dinner, Mushroom &amp; spinach pie. Sorry I cut it before I could take a pic..... I really need to get better at remembering to photograph what I do!</em></td></tr></tbody></table>]]></content>
        <category label="pastry" term="pastry"/>
        <category label="my vegetarian cookbook" term="my vegetarian cookbook"/>
        <category label="cooking" term="cooking"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Graft copolymers consisting of poly(3-hexylthiophene)]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2024/May/graft-cps</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2024/May/graft-cps"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jadranka Travas-Sejdic is a polymer scientist and professor over at the University of Auckland. As a condition of PhD submission, you needed to send through a form including five nominated examiners. Jadranka was one of them. At this point, I am not sure if she was my reviewer but I admire her a lot and if she was, I am hoping that she enjoyed reading my thesis.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Jadranka Travas-Sejdic is a polymer scientist and professor over at the University of Auckland. As a condition of PhD submission, you needed to send through a form including five nominated examiners. Jadranka was one of them. At this point, I am not sure if she was my reviewer but I admire her a lot and if she was, I am hoping that she enjoyed reading my thesis.</p><p>Recently, Jadrank's group released a paper, where they synthesised a polymer brush or "<em>graft</em> copolymer. A polymer brush looks like a bottlebrush plant on the molecular level. In this work, 3-hexylthiophene was polymerised using chemical oxidation with  FeCl<sub>3</sub>. Following, 2-thiophene acetic acid was added to the reaction mixture to create a carboxylic acid terminated group. The carboxylic acid groups were then grafted to a gelatin polymer using EDC/NHS coupling. This method covalently cross-links a carboxylic acid with a terminal amine group, forming a peptide bond. The % of P3HT in the graft copolymer was determined to be 9.05% using UV-vis spectroscopy. A calibration curve of P3HT was generated, which allowed the mass to be determined and thus the overall wt % in the polymer. </p><table><thead><tr><th align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/graft_cp-e3c2d29b1b2b60c036e36b475a20041f.jpeg" width="1280" height="703" class="img_ev3q"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="center">*Fig 1. (a) Synthesis of P3HT from 3HT via chemical oxidation and then reaction with 2-thiopheneacetic acid, (b) covalent attachment of P3HT to gelatin to create a brush structure.</td></tr></tbody></table><p>Now, when I think of polymer brush, I think of good mechanical properties (see <a href="/science/polymer-science/structures/molecular-polymer-brushes">Molecular Polymer Brushes</a>)! Which means these types of materials could be used as potential pressure sensors.The conjugated nature of P3HT also means that it can be used as an electronic device.</p><p>Through a THF/H<sub>2</sub>O cosolvent, thin films (9.05 wt% P3HT) were dropcast on Au electrodes. The conductivity of this system was determined to be 1.64 ± 0.02 x 10<sup>-7</sup> S/cm. In contrast, a second copolymer that contained 1.23% P3HT, exhibited "no appreciable conductivity" likely due to the poor network formation or intercalation of the alkyl chains of P3HT to prevent interchain charge transport. Exposure to a collagenase type II allowed for cleavage of the peptide bonds between the gelatin and P3HT. The hydrophobicity of P3HT meant that it would form spherical nanoparticles once the polymer brush degraded, with gelatin as the hydrophillic polymer, forming a corona around the particle and preventing toxicity from the P3HT. </p><p>Now, this work is cool. I love groups that do little tricks to make new polymers from existing stuff. However, I see study after study that create new materials or do some neat chemistries and it ends up nowhere. We already know the importance of biofunctionalising conducting polymers to create better biocompatible materials for a biointerface. I'd like to see someone commercialise this stuff! or create a device with it. </p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="reference">Reference<a href="#reference" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Reference" title="Direct link to Reference">​</a></h3><p><a href="https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acsami.4c02174" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sun, X.;  Chan, E. W. C.;  Chen, Q.;  Kirby, N.;  Yang, J.;  Mata, J. P.;  Kingston, R. L.;  Barker, D.;  Domigan, L.; Travas-Sejdic, J., Copolymers of Gelatin-graft-poly(3-hexylthiophene) for Transient Electronics. ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces 2024, 16 (18), 23872-23884.</a></p>]]></content>
        <category label="conducting polymers" term="conducting polymers"/>
        <category label="science" term="science"/>
        <category label="chemistry" term="chemistry"/>
        <category label="biocompatibility" term="biocompatibility"/>
        <category label="graft copolymers" term="graft copolymers"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spinach and cheese "triangles"]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2024/May/spinach_cheese_triangles</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2024/May/spinach_cheese_triangles"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Preparing the puff pastry]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="preparing-the-puff-pastry">Preparing the puff pastry<a href="#preparing-the-puff-pastry" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Preparing the puff pastry" title="Direct link to Preparing the puff pastry">​</a></h2><p><em>22.5.24</em></p><p>It was Wednesday last week. I had just prepared a butter tofu and rice for dinner, but it was only 5 pm (we usually eat at 6 pm). As I was cleaning up, I had a desire to bake more bread. But I didn't want to make anymore bread, especially considering that I still had a dough in the freezer! Therefore, I decided I would make puff pastry for dinner the following night. The initial recipe that I went with wanted 250 g of butter! I cut it down to 170g and added a excess of water and refrigerated for a longer period of time:</p><p align="center"> 250 g flour<br>1/4 tsp salt<br>170 g butter<br>2 cup water<br></p><p><em>extra flour for dusting</em> </p><p></p><p>So basically, I blended the flour and butter to make a crumbly consistency and then the water to create a dough. It was meant to be very crumbly, but because I added too much water, it was very sticky. I needed to compensate by adding more flour. Once the dough was very crumbly, I rolled it out into a long rectangle and then folded several times. I covered it in plastic wrap and placed in the fridge. </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="preparing-and-cooking-the-triangles">Preparing and cooking the triangles<a href="#preparing-and-cooking-the-triangles" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Preparing and cooking the triangles" title="Direct link to Preparing and cooking the triangles">​</a></h2><p><em>23.5.24</em> </p><p>Next, I pulled the dough out of the fridge, unwrapped it and rolled it to be a little thinner. I divided it into 6x rectangles. Note: this dough was so sticky that they definitely were not rectangles! I prepared the pastry filling as follows: </p><p align="center">1 Garlic<br>1/2 onion<br>handful of spinach<br>1 tsp bread crumbs<br>1/4 cup tasty cheese<br>1/4 cup mozarella<br>1 egg</p><p>Basically, in about 20 g of butter, I fried up garlic and onion and spinach. It was cooled slightly, then i added all the remaining ingredients and mixed well. </p><p>I then added ~1 heaped table spoon to the pastries and folded as best as I could into triangles.... No they were not triangles, but triangle equivalent?</p><table><thead><tr><th align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/pastry1-12817e97a2385f58bc730ee3f755e6dd.svg" width="3644" height="1531" class="img_ev3q"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="center"><em>Img caption: Before and after the puff pastries were baked.</em></td></tr></tbody></table><h1>What did I learn?</h1><p>The triangles were tasty! However, I will do things differently next time. I will cut out more of the butter if possible and swap for a bit of olive oil oil, so that the flavour more closely resembles pizza dough, rather than biscuits. These pastries were very sweet and so I would have liked to add a bit more salt to make them go well with the savoury filling.</p>]]></content>
        <category label="cooking" term="cooking"/>
        <category label="bread" term="bread"/>
        <category label="pastry" term="pastry"/>
        <category label="my vegetarian cookbook" term="my vegetarian cookbook"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gluten intolerance]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2024/May/gluten-intolerance</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2024/May/gluten-intolerance"/>
        <updated>2024-05-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bread is subjectively the best thing to exist on Earth. Do you agree? Well about 5-10% of you will not agree. This is because gluten intolerance is a fairly prevalent allergy. Celiac disease is the name given to a gluten intolerance, which is diagnosed in about 1% of people wordwide. People with this disease experience vomiting, bloating, abdominal pain, numbness in the hands and feet among many other symptoms, in response to gluten ingestion. Why does this occur?]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Bread is subjectively the best thing to exist on Earth. Do you agree? Well about 5-10% of you will not agree. This is because gluten intolerance is a fairly prevalent allergy. Celiac disease is the name given to a gluten intolerance, which is diagnosed in about 1% of people wordwide. People with this disease experience vomiting, bloating, abdominal pain, numbness in the hands and feet among many other symptoms, in response to gluten ingestion. Why does this occur?</p><p>Celiac disease is commonly inherited through the genes. One genetic marker of celiac is the human leukocyte antigen (HLA)-DQ2 and HLA-DQ8 genotype. About 30% of people will express this genotype, however, only 1-3% of people will develop the disease. These two genes present on Antigen-Presenting Cells (APCs) to produce an immune response when exposed to peptides from Gliadin.</p><p>As I explained in my previous bread post, gluten is composed of gliadin, which is the harmful component to people with celiac. Gliadin is difficult to digest, even in healthy humans, due to the presence of prolamins (a group of plant storage proteins). These proteins are generally hydrophobic (or water-hating), with the central region composed mostly of glutamine and proline amino acids. As a result, gliaden will pass into the intestinal barrier. The presence of gliadin in the small intestine produces an inflammtory response, where cells will release tissue transamidase (tTG), often the reason why we would experience bloating in response to breads. tTg expression is increased in celliac sufferers.</p><table><thead><tr><th align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/t-tg-89320866901139e2a22b9e89b7763514.jpg" width="849" height="622" class="img_ev3q"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="center"><em>Fig 1. (a) Crosslinking of glutamine and lysine to form a high molecular weight polymer or (b) deamidation of glutamine to form glutamate which is negatively charged at physiological pH. Both reactions are catalysed by tTG</em>.</td></tr></tbody></table><p>Once released from cells, tTG crosslinks a protein with a glutamine residue (in this case, the gliadin) to a protein with a lysine group, via a peptide bond. This cross-linking is an important step that leads to insoluble protein aggregates, which can be cleared from the body. However, it can also convert glutamine to glutamic acid in a process called deamidation. </p><p>Deamidation of gliadin produces negatively charged peptides at physiological pH (7.4-7.6), which then has a high affinity for HLA-DQ2 and HLA-DQ8. The binding of the glutamic acid to the HLA proteins, results in T-cell stimulation, followed by release of proinflammatory cytokines. This inflammatory response leads to the destruction of the intestinal villi, which are responsible for absorbing nutrients.In addition, people with celliac disease, antibodies are produced in response to the tTG release, further invoking the limitation in gliadin digestion and thus, increasing the prevalence of inflammation. </p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="references">References<a href="#references" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to References" title="Direct link to References">​</a></h3><ol><li>Sha, X., et al., The prolamins, from structure, property, to the function in encapsulation and delivery of bioactive compounds. Food Hydrocolloids, 2024. 149: p. 109508.</li><li>Aboulaghras, S., et al., Pathophysiology and immunogenetics of celiac disease. Clinica Chimica Acta, 2022. 528: p. 74-83.1. </li><li>Lerner, A. and C. Benzvi, "Let Food Be Thy Medicine": Gluten and Potential Role in Neurodegeneration. Cells, 2021. 10(4). </li><li>Parzanese, I., et al., Celiac disease: From pathophysiology to treatment. World J Gastrointest Pathophysiol, 2017. 8(2): p. 27-38.</li><li>Lorand, L. and R.M. Graham, Transglutaminases: crosslinking enzymes with pleiotropic functions. Nature Reviews Molecular Cell Biology, 2003. 4(2): p. 140-156.</li></ol>]]></content>
        <category label="bread" term="bread"/>
        <category label="gluten" term="gluten"/>
        <category label="science" term="science"/>
        <category label="biochemistry" term="biochemistry"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inductively Coupled Plasma (ICP) mass spectrometry (MS)/Optical emission spectroscopy (OES)]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2024/May/icp_</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2024/May/icp_"/>
        <updated>2024-05-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recently I started a position as a lab technician with Australian National Fabrication Facility (ANFF). One of the requirements of this position is to maintain the ICP (Fig 1). Therefore, I decided to write a short post here about ICP, which I will update with the various things that I have learned along the way.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently I started a position as a lab technician with Australian National Fabrication Facility (ANFF). One of the requirements of this position is to maintain the ICP (Fig 1). Therefore, I decided to write a short post here about ICP, which I will update with the various things that I have learned along the way. </p><table><thead><tr><th align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/icp-fig-2-03dffa70c83f6fd9a547e4522d46aa62.jpg" width="4713" height="2884" class="img_ev3q"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="center"><em>Fig 1. The ICP in my lab at the University of Wollongong, with the labelled components</em></td></tr></tbody></table><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-is-icp">What is ICP?<a href="#what-is-icp" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What is ICP?" title="Direct link to What is ICP?">​</a></h2><p>Inductively coupled plasma (ICP) mass spectrometry (MS) or optical emission spectroscopy (OES) is a method of elemental analysis which utilises a plasma source. In ICP-MS, the ions are directly measured. In contract, ICP-OES uses an optical spectrometer to measure the photons emitted as they pass through the plasma. While both methods are extremely fast to use, cheap and straightforward, the ICP-OES has a higher sensitivity to detection. </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="how-does-icp-work">How does ICP work?<a href="#how-does-icp-work" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to How does ICP work?" title="Direct link to How does ICP work?">​</a></h2><table><thead><tr><th align="center"><img loading="lazy" alt="Schematic of ICP" src="/assets/images/fig1-icp-b973c0fd8a33d264862421400b87c4e1.jpeg" width="1280" height="462" class="img_ev3q"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="center"><em>Figure 2. Schematic of ICP: (a) engineered setup and (b) behaviour of the sample inside the sample channel. Images taken from (Hou and Jones) and (McCurdy and Potter)</em></td></tr></tbody></table><p>A schematic of an ICP is displayed in Fig 2. The liquid sample is injected into a spray chamber which is converted to an aerosol via a nebuliser. During this process, only the very fine particles are injected into the inductor. In the inductor, the sample aerosol is further dried and vapourised due to the high temperatures (10000 K) in the sample carrier. In this process, all chemical bonds are broken, allowing for the vapourisation of each individual atom (Fig 2b). The free atoms collide with plasma, allowing them to transition to an excited state. Upon relaxation to ground state, the ions/atoms will emit a photon of characteristic energies, which can be used to determine the elemental origin of the ions. The total number of photons emitted is proportional to the concentration.</p><p>The ionisation plasma is typically argon gas as it is chemically inert and contains a high proportion of cations and electrons with a high electron density. In the set up shown in Fig 2a, radiofrequency (RF) is applied to a coil which produces “seed” electrons which are accelerated and collide with argon gas to form argon plasma and electrons:</p><p align="center"> Ar(g) → Ar<sup>+</sup> + e<sup>-</sup> </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="about-sample-preparation">About sample preparation<a href="#about-sample-preparation" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to About sample preparation" title="Direct link to About sample preparation">​</a></h2><p>Solubilised solutions (aqueous or organic) are required to perform ICP analysis. Therefore, samples (&lt;0.2 %&gt;) are typically treated with nitric acid (HNO<sub>3</sub>) or HCl, in a process referred to as "acid digestion".  Sample concentrations of &lt;0.2% are crucial to avoid any matrix effects.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="matrix-effects">Matrix effects<a href="#matrix-effects" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Matrix effects" title="Direct link to Matrix effects">​</a></h2><p>Matrix effects are interferences in the analysis due ton signal dift caused by the deposition of solids on the sample apertures or signal suppression caused by salt ions. The typical salt interference is caused by oxide formation, which seems to reduce the ion flow and promotes clogging at the sample cone (the interface that analyses ion extraction). With years of research, matrix effects have typically solved through the use of OES compared to MS. ICP-OES relies on photon emission rather than ion acceleration, which makes it less susceptible to interferences. </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="advantages-of-icp-compared-to-other-elemental-analyses">Advantages of ICP compared to other elemental analyses<a href="#advantages-of-icp-compared-to-other-elemental-analyses" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Advantages of ICP compared to other elemental analyses" title="Direct link to Advantages of ICP compared to other elemental analyses">​</a></h2><p>As ICP heats to very high temperatures, samples undergo more efficient vaporisation, atomisation and excitation. This allows for a wider range of elements to be analysed by ICP. In addition, the high temperature means that there is less water vapour present, in turn reducing the concentration of oxygen species and thus a lower level of matrix interferences caused by oxide formation. </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="references">References<a href="#references" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to References" title="Direct link to References">​</a></h2><ol><li>Ammann, A.A., Inductively coupled plasma mass spectrometry (ICP MS): a versatile tool. Journal of Mass Spectrometry, 2007. 42(4): p. 419-427.<br></li><li>Hou, X. and B.T. Jones, Inductively Coupled Plasma Optical Emission Spectrometry, in Encyclopedia of Analytical Chemistry. 2000, John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd: Chichester. p. 9468-6485.<br></li><li>McCurdy, E. and D. Potter, Optimising ICP-MS for the determination of trace metals in high matrix samples. Spectroscopy Europe, 2001. 13: p. 14+16-20.<br></li><li>Kopru, S. and M. Soylak, Inductively coupled plasma-mass spectrometry (ICP-MS) detection of trace metal contents of children cosmetics. Optical and Quantum Electronics, 2024. 56(3): p. 399.</li></ol>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Almost there]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/12/15/2023-12/</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/12/15/2023-12/"/>
        <updated>2023-12-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's been just over a month since I've wrote something in my blog.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It's been just over a month since I've wrote something in my blog. </p><p>For the last month and a half, I have been working through the comments that I received back. It's been a real tough time, because there were a lot of comments. I honestly felt like everything I knew about my topic was wrong. I have been reading so much and redoing all my figures/analyses. Each day, I started work at 7 am and continued until 10 pm. I even spent all my weekends working on it. Until finally, I felt proud of my thesis! Now, it is being reviewed by one of my supervisors. </p><p>The plan now is to write a couple of research papers. However, my current dilemma is that I dont want to write a paper if my supervisors do not agree with what I wrote in my thesis.</p>]]></content>
        <category label="PhD" term="PhD"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Updates]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/10/31/2023-10/</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/10/31/2023-10/"/>
        <updated>2023-10-31T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the weekend, Nick and I headed to the Hunter Valley for a wedding. It was great to get away, and now I am feeling fresh to resume writing.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the weekend, Nick and I headed to the <a href="/life/trips/hunter-valley">Hunter Valley</a> for a wedding. It was great to get away, and now I am feeling fresh to resume writing.</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PhD update]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/10/25/2023-10/</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/10/25/2023-10/"/>
        <updated>2023-10-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[- [x] As it stands, I have completed writing my PhD thesis. Below is a table summary of the chapters, with type of chapter, number of words (in total, incl. references, and figures) and number of pages]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul class="contains-task-list containsTaskList_mC6p"><li class="task-list-item"><input type="checkbox" checked="" disabled=""> <!-- -->As it stands, I have completed writing my PhD thesis. Below is a table summary of the chapters, with type of chapter, number of words (in total, incl. references, and figures) and number of pages</li><li class="task-list-item"><input type="checkbox" disabled=""> <!-- -->I still have a few more experiments to conduct for Research Chapter 5 and 7. </li><li class="task-list-item"><input type="checkbox" disabled=""> <!-- -->I still need to write up the supporting information (which will be a lot)</li><li class="task-list-item"><input type="checkbox" disabled=""> <!-- -->I still need to write papers. </li><li class="task-list-item"><input type="checkbox" disabled=""> <!-- -->I plan to complete my thesis and send by Friday 27 Oct. </li></ul><h5 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="table-summary-of-my-phd-thesis">Table Summary of my PhD thesis:<a href="#table-summary-of-my-phd-thesis" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Table Summary of my PhD thesis:" title="Direct link to Table Summary of my PhD thesis:">​</a></h5><table><thead><tr><th align="left">Chapter</th><th align="center">Content</th><th align="center">Words</th><th align="right">Pages</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left">1</td><td align="center">Intro</td><td align="center">11937</td><td align="right">36</td></tr><tr><td align="left">2</td><td align="center">Methods</td><td align="center">9150</td><td align="right">27</td></tr><tr><td align="left">3</td><td align="center">Research</td><td align="center">6289</td><td align="right">29</td></tr><tr><td align="left">4</td><td align="center">Research</td><td align="center">11257</td><td align="right">39</td></tr><tr><td align="left">5</td><td align="center">Research</td><td align="center">6351</td><td align="right">27</td></tr><tr><td align="left">6</td><td align="center">Research</td><td align="center">6887</td><td align="right">24</td></tr><tr><td align="left">7</td><td align="center">Research</td><td align="center">9908</td><td align="right">34</td></tr><tr><td align="left">8</td><td align="center">Conclusions</td><td align="center">3700</td><td align="right">11</td></tr><tr><td align="left">Total</td><td align="center"></td><td align="center">65479</td><td align="right">227</td></tr></tbody></table>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More content]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/10/22/2023-10/</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/10/22/2023-10/"/>
        <updated>2023-10-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A few updates include:]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few updates include: </p><ul><li><a href="/phd/tips-for-writing">Tips for writing</a> in PhD section</li><li><a href="/life/surf-lifesaving/patrol-days">Recap of patrol</a> in Life section / Surf Lifesaving</li><li><a href="/phd/pros-cons">Pros and cons for starting a PhD</a> in PhD section</li><li>Added <a href="/life/food-and-drink/restaurants-and-bars/rocksalt-menai">Rock Salt, Menai</a> to Life section / Food and drink / Restaurants and bars</li><li>Added <a href="/life/trips/hunter-valley">Trips to the Hunter Valley</a> to Life section / Trips</li></ul>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Another Saturday]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/10/21/2023-10/</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/10/21/2023-10/"/>
        <updated>2023-10-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Updates:]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Updates:</p><ol><li><a href="/phd/starting-over-a-phd">If I could start my PhD again</a></li></ol>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some days are productive, some days are not]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/08/25/2023-08/</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/08/25/2023-08/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last Thursday, my supervisor cancelled my weekly PhD meeting and instead requested that we sit down and go through my thesis and decide what we need to do moving forward. Both Pawel and David agreed that I should not be doing anymore lab work and just focus on writing my thesis! There it is "only focus on writing".]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last Thursday, my supervisor cancelled my weekly PhD meeting and instead requested that we sit down and go through my thesis and decide what we need to do moving forward. Both Pawel and David agreed that I should not be doing anymore lab work and just focus on writing my thesis! There it is "only focus on writing". </p><p><em>Productivity:</em> From Friday onwards, I started writing all my results down. I wrote a lot in the span of 4 days and I felt that if I kept writing then I could be finished by the end of the month. </p><p><em>Unproductive:</em> On Wednesday 23 August, I had a really bad day of writing. By 3 pm, I was on the lounge watching a TV show. I did not attempt to recommence writing for the rest of the evening. It really messed me around on Thursday. At this rate, I won't finish my PhD in time!</p><p><em>A tip to improve productivity:</em> I was lucky this week in my Thursday meeting. I got a few tips from my supervisors about writing. David commented that the best thing to do when you are not feeling like thinking is to write out the methods chapter. He was right. Writing out my methods chapter is a simple way to get myself in the mood of writing and to continue my writing routine. </p><p><em>More unproductivity:</em> This morning, I went driving around Wollongong to try and get a quote to fix my passenger-side mirror of my car. Grant from Fernhill Smash Repairs told me that he would be in touch later in the afternoon. NOTE: the passenger side-mirror is no longer afixed to the car as I nipped it off on the way home from the beach yesterday. Without a passenger side-mirror, I cannot drive my car. This means that I can't drive to North Wollongong beach! I need to paddle in the morning for me to feel fresh for a day of writing! This screwed up my whole day. At 10 am, I gave up on writing and decided to head to Innovation Campus to get some data off the computers. I ran there and remained until 4 pm..... and that is all I did today.</p><p>In the evening, Nick and I walked to <a href="/life/food-and-drink/craft-beer/illawarra/barrel-shephard">The Barrel Shephard</a> for dinner and drinks. I felt aweful, like I didn't deserve to be going out after a day of very little work and progress. Note to future self: stop going into the lab, save it for the weekend or afternoons.</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A very stupid thing]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/08/08/2023-08/</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/08/08/2023-08/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When I woke up at 5.55 am, it seemed like it was going to be another cracker of a day. I prepared for teaching, went for a run, did some stretching and showered all before 8.30 am. I was more than ready to make huge progress today!]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I woke up at 5.55 am, it seemed like it was going to be another cracker of a day. I prepared for teaching, went for a run, did some stretching and showered all before 8.30 am. I was more than ready to make huge progress today! </p><p>I arrived at work at 9 am and from the minute I began to do things in the lab, everything went wrong. I couldn't get any good data. Around 10 am, I went to get help to fix a cable for my potentiostat (as the wires lost connection to reduce the signal). However, I was unsuccessful in getting help. A colleague/researcher said to meet her at 3 pm to repair the cable; but I couldnt wait this long as I was due to teach at 1.30 til 4.30 pm (Week 3 of Semester 2).. </p><p>By this point it was 11 am - I was feeling really tired and unmotivated. </p><p>My first thought was to go home. I lost motivation when I realised that I would only be home for 1 hour before having to leave again. Instead, I pulled out my soft back warmer from my draw and used it as a pillow. I put my head down on the desk and had an hour nap. </p><p>I woke up less tired than before, but really groggy. I packed my safety glasses and water bottle into my handbag and walked towards my car, then drove to the main campus. Travel between the innovation campus and the main campus is really tedious and it is often difficult to find parking in the middle of the day. </p><p>I was parked and ready to get out of the car at 1 pm. I walked towards Panzinis, a cafe located in front of the UOW library. I go here for coffee because they offer staff discounts and I love discouts! I ordered my coffee and it was made within 5 minutes. It was a rather pleasant experience - too bad that I was not in a good mood. </p><p>The undergraduate chemistry labs are located in building 21 on level 3. I headed here after I was handed my coffee - but I was at least 20 minutes early. When I walked into the lab, it was empty abar one demonstrator - Sue. I chatted for less than a minute before rereading over my emails that said I was only rostered for Week 9. In sheer disbelief, I spent a few minutes researching my emails and was convinced that I showed up for no reason! In embarrassment, I left and drove to North Wollongong beach. "Wow" I thought. "How stupid". "Why didn't I read my emails?" </p><p>I was pretty relieved though, because I didn't really want to teach. I don't need the extra funds that bad and it's not worth taking time away from my writing. Excited that I could fix the potentiostat, I also sent an email to a colleague, indicating my error and that I would be there at 3 pm. </p><p>Just as I was about to get out of my car and go for a dip in the ocean to calm down my anxiety and embarrassment, I received an email from Giel (the subject coordinator) who asked me to come back because I was rostered to work. Can you believe how embarrassed I was after this? It took me 15 minutes to return, park and walk to the labs. I quickly walked into the service room, dodging the lines of students waiting to collect a pH probe for their experiment. I threw on a red lab coat, my safety glasses and grabbed a pen. </p><p>I apologised several times to Giel and I literally felt like slapping my forehead because it was such a stupid thing that happened. The worst thing though, was sending a third email to my colleague telling her that I was wrong and I was meant to teach! </p><p>The labs were very slow and very basic. The students were working on acid-base titrations. In that moment, I thought that it wasn't too bad. I actually enjoyed it.  I'm just glad that I don't have to teach all the time. The labs ended at 4.30 pm. I drove straight home and relaxed until dinner time. </p><p>I honestly feel like I wasted the whole day.</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rewarding myself]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/08/04/2023-08/</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/08/04/2023-08/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lately, I have been freaking out with the amount of work still left in my PhD. Today, I had planned to have a writing day but I realised as I opened various thesis chapters, that I have actually written a lot! At 11 am, I decided to head into the lab to try to resynthesise a monomer for my second research chapter. While searching the freezer for my materials, I came across a molecule that I had synthesised previously, but never used. It was a dibromo-compound that was initially synthesised for a grignard reaction.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Lately, I have been freaking out with the amount of work still left in my PhD. Today, I had planned to have a writing day but I realised as I opened various thesis chapters, that I have actually written a lot! At 11 am, I decided to head into the lab to try to resynthesise a monomer for my second research chapter. While searching the freezer for my materials, I came across a molecule that I had synthesised previously, but never used. It was a dibromo-compound that was initially synthesised for a grignard reaction. </p><p>For fun, I set up a 1 mL (200 mg) scale <a href="/science/polymer-science/synthesis/darp">direct arylation polymerisation</a>. For the rest of the day, I felt so happy and accomplished. I feel so excited to work this polymer up and characterise it. </p><p>To hear more about this, and see the fun I have with these reactions, visit <a href="/phd/side-projects">side projects</a>. </p><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/dhap-461e005e73beee5a4a5377372feae3c5.jpeg" width="60%" class="centered-image img_ev3q">]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Garlic & Rosemary Pull apart bread]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/08/02/2023-08/</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/08/02/2023-08/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's already August! Wow, where has the time gone? Five months left until I need to submit my PhD thesis.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It's already August! Wow, where has the time gone? Five months left until I need to submit my PhD thesis. </p><p>I arrived home from work after an unsuccessful day in the lab. The electrodes attached to my potentiostat were disfunctioning. I spent my 3 hours of lab time, trying to trouble shoot the problem. With the help of one of the guys in the workshop, I was able to fix the electrode. However, upon a "dummy test", the signal was not strong. I gave up, and decided to go home and not waste anymore time. </p><p>I arrived home and prepared a quiche for dinner. I was feeling inspired by Emma (as over the weekend, she made a really awesome scrambled eggs). The egg filling alone contained some butter and rosemary. </p><p>After I finished preparing dinner, I was still in the mood to cook - anything to avoid working on my thesis! I decided to prepare tomorrow nights dinner as well. </p><p>I don't know about you, but I get tired of eating similar things all the time. I feel like it is super boring and not creative at all. While I was having these thoughts, I had finished the rest of our loaf of bread. That's when I was inspired to make some bread. </p><p>I remember when I was much younger, around 15 years old and would often bake various things for my family. I enjoyed baking a lot - from bread to cakes. However, I saw so many people around me who were a lot better. I often compared myself to others and it really demotivated me to cook (Yes, I always wanted to be the best). I wonder what life would have been like if I didn't compare myself and just did the things that I enjoyed - because I enjoyed them. </p><p>Maybe my enjoyment of baking and "creative cooking" is the reason that I chose chemistry. I always wonder what drove me to stay in chemistry. I usually say that it was because I got the best marks for the least amount of effort - which is probably true. Now, I am thinking that it was also because I was using my hands to create something. Synthesis is very similar to cooking: a step by step process to create something wonderful. </p><p>The funny thing is though, I struggle so much to follow recipes. The same thing applies in the lab: I struggle a lot to follow new synthetic protocols. This caused so much stress during my undergrad: as I didn't perform as well as some of the other students. Somehow I have made it through and am almost finished a PhD in chemistry! Sometimes I forget how amazing it is that I've made it this far. Dani had to remind me earlier today when we were discussing my PhD. </p><p>Anyway, the <a href="https://sallysbakingaddiction.com/rosemary-garlic-pull-apart-bread/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Garlic &amp; Rosemary pull apart bread</a> that I made was taken from Sally's baking addiction. There is some good stuff on her blog! I also listed the procedure that I used (because I never follow a procedure well and there are always things that I modify or change) in my <a href="/life/food-and-drink/cooking/pull-apart-bread">Pull-apart bread</a> post. </p><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/garlic-rosemary-bread-22e55f4fb8219f5ec83cee62fce49026.jpeg" width="50%" class="centered-image img_ev3q">]]></content>
        <category label="cooking" term="cooking"/>
        <category label="My vegetarian cookbook" term="My vegetarian cookbook"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changing my attitude]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/28/2023-07/</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/28/2023-07/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It didn't take long to change my attitude once I acknowledged it.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It didn't take long to change my attitude once I acknowledged it. </p><p>Over the last few days, I have had time to reflect on my actions and my feelings and I realised that I need to be kinder to myself and try to think of "criticism" as "feedback". My Supervisors have 50 years of experience over me, so I need to stop comparing myself to other people. Instead, I need to compare myself from the start of my PhD to myself now. I am very proud of how much I've grown as a person and a scientist. </p><p>My feelings of doom have become more optimistic as I feel excited to finish and get a job in the real world! It's funny how a little bit of perspective can make the world around you seem more positive. </p><p>This weekend, I am taking a break and we are heading up to Terrigal for Emma's 30th birthday and Hens weekend! Should be good.</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Office critique]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/25/2023-07/</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/25/2023-07/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Currently I am writing my thesis and subsequent manuscripts. I have so many emotions towards finishing my PhD.  At times I am really enjoying writing, and at other times I just want it all to finish. But the thought of finishing my PhD gives me a lot of anxiety, as this is all I've known for a long time. I fear that I will be terrible at any job I get in the future. Right now, I justify my work as "I am just a student", I am learning. What if, when I finish my PhD, I can't find anything that I am good at? What if I can't find a job that I like? This really scares me and I often worry about it.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Currently I am writing my thesis and subsequent manuscripts. I have so many emotions towards finishing my PhD.  At times I am really enjoying writing, and at other times I just want it all to finish. But the thought of finishing my PhD gives me a lot of anxiety, as this is all I've known for a long time. I fear that I will be terrible at any job I get in the future. Right now, I justify my work as "I am just a student", I am learning. What if, when I finish my PhD, I can't find anything that I am good at? What if I can't find a job that I like? This really scares me and I often worry about it. </p><p>At 9 am this morning, I had a meeting with my supervisors, to talk about my long awaited, first manuscript. We spoke about the structure and story of the research paper, and their feedback was very helpful. I'm kicking myself that I didn't show them sooner and push for this to be published 2 years ago (when the work was originally done).</p><p>During this meeting, I didn't realise that I was figgeting a lot. I was playing with my hair, biting my nails, moving around and just sitting very casually. Afterwards, it was pointed it out, and I was really embarrassed. I am glad that he said something to me though, because I feel like in future meetings I can pay closer attention to it. </p><p>In my defense though, my PhD feels very casual. I feel like my supervisors are my family; but maybe I am taking my comfort for granted. I also feel like it is not my work place. I am not treated like a staff member, nor do I get the same treatment as a staff member. </p><p>I went home after the meeting feeling really embarrased and a bit upset. To be honest, at the moment, I don't like certain things about myself; like my current connection with friends or my behaviour when I am stressed or anxious. I feel like I've spent a lot of time complaining about things and blaming others for my bad attitude. I need to retake control of my actions, stop complaining and just get stuff done. </p><p>I worked through comments for the rest of the day and then around 4 pm, I decided to go out for a run. Running has always helped me cope with my anxiety. I ran 10 km - which is the most I've ran since the marathon back in July 2022. My mood significantly improved since the run; however, not long after, I started to feel a bit sad. I want things to change. I want to be better.</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Date night]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/23/2023-07/</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/23/2023-07/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last night, Nick and I went to the movies to watch Oppenheimer, followed by dinner at Din Tai Fung in Miranda. The movie was really good, it told the story of Robert J Oppenheimer, a theoretical phyicist who helped to build the atomic bomb. I read some other reviews online. They say that Christopher Nolan got a lot of the biography right, with only a little bit of dramatisation.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last night, Nick and I went to the movies to watch Oppenheimer, followed by dinner at Din Tai Fung in Miranda. The movie was really good, it told the story of Robert J Oppenheimer, a theoretical phyicist who helped to build the atomic bomb. I read some other reviews online. They say that Christopher Nolan got a lot of the biography right, with only a little bit of dramatisation. </p><p>We sat on the beds at the front of the cinema. It was so comfortable and I was so happy that we chose those seats because it was a 3 hour movie! The alternative seating would've been wildly uncomfortable. </p><p>Dinner afterwards was also really great. We had dumplings and steamed buns! Yummy. </p><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/dumplings-buns-3e28292d534284e77a7f98dc5ba26e79.jpeg" width="40%" class="centered-image img_ev3q">]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My shoulder]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/17/2023-07/</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/17/2023-07/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An update on my shoulder: On 31 May, I fell off my paddle board and hit the right side of my body on the ground (the waves were very dumping at NW beach). As a result, I could barely move my arm or shoulder. As of last week, my shoulder was not in good shape - even after 5 weeks! Last week, I went for an xray. The doctor says that there may be some form of a fracture in my scapula bone. She requested that I get a CT scan. The CT scan confirmed that I have a fracture of the acromion. To my luck though, it is not located in the joint, nor does it affect the joint. Now it's just a waiting game to heal.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An update on my shoulder: On 31 May, I fell off my paddle board and hit the right side of my body on the ground (the waves were very dumping at NW beach). As a result, I could barely move my arm or shoulder. As of last week, my shoulder was not in good shape - even after 5 weeks! Last week, I went for an xray. The doctor says that there may be some form of a fracture in my scapula bone. She requested that I get a CT scan. The CT scan confirmed that I have a fracture of the acromion. To my luck though, it is not located in the joint, nor does it affect the joint. Now it's just a waiting game to heal.</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Update]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/16/2023-07/</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/16/2023-07/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-16T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's been really busy lately. For my PhD, I have been doing a lot of Raman Spectroscopy to characterise my materials in my project. I have also been writing a manuscript. Finally, on Friday, I submitted the manuscipt to my supervisors.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It's been really busy lately. For my PhD, I have been doing a lot of Raman Spectroscopy to characterise my materials in my project. I have also been writing a manuscript. Finally, on Friday, I submitted the manuscipt to my supervisors. </p><p>I am feeling nervous about the manuscript, and that they will not read it. Only last Thursday, David asked me about a manuscript. I told him it was on the way. So hopefully, since I've sent it through, they will all read it and give me helpful feedback. </p><p>In other news, I've been practicing surfing only a little. Yesterday, I stood up consistently for waves. My shoulder still hurts but it is getting better, slowly. </p><p>New posts: </p><ul><li><a href="/life/food-and-drink/craft-beer/illawarra/priciple-brewing">Principle Brewing</a></li><li><a href="/life/food-and-drink/cooking/mediterranian-bowl">Mediterranian Bowl</a></li><li><a href="/life/food-and-drink/cooking/west-african-peanut-soup">West African Peanut Soup</a></li></ul><p>Also, a long awaited comment bar has now been introduced into each side-bar home.</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[History of carly.cool]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/06/2023-07/</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/06/2023-07/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are live with the new website!]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We are live with the new website! </p><p>Let's not forget how the homepage looked just yesterday!</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="The first homepage of carly.cool" src="/assets/images/version1-website-701117e0af7c74607570009258cf9c9b.png" width="1418" height="1253" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Website!]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/new-website</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/new-website"/>
        <updated>2023-07-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Now, Carly.cool runs using Docusaurus.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Now, Carly.cool runs using Docusaurus.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Carly Baker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Roosters vs. Raiders NRL game]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/06/25/2023-06/</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/06/25/2023-06/"/>
        <updated>2023-06-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[football]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" alt="football" src="/assets/images/food-football-bde9470f49847f8ce4e5303100d15759.png" width="2044" height="939" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Roosters vs. Raiders game. Nick's dad had 4 spare corporate box tickets. Nick invited Nathan and Emma to come with us.</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Back to reality]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/06/26/2023-06/</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/06/26/2023-06/"/>
        <updated>2023-06-26T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[chip on a beenbag]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" alt="chip on a beenbag" src="/assets/images/chip-on-beenbag-2a02c87067f687f6c010ca68a6bbcdb7.png" width="3419" height="1475" class="img_ev3q">
Standard Monday workday. I feel too tired to go to the lab. I decided to work from home. All day, I have not done any thesis writing for my PhD , only updating my blog. I feel very nervous to go into the lab tomorrow. My supervisors want me to go to NZLD to do some lab work. After my trip to <a href="/life/trips/usa">USA 2023</a>, I don't want to go anywhere for the rest of the year. It is too windy to do any outside activities but I am feeling stressed from my lack of water time - swimming or paddling.</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zayne's 1st birthday & Baptism]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/06/24/2023-06/</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/06/24/2023-06/"/>
        <updated>2023-06-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On this day, I arrived home from USA and headed straight to mum's to get ready for Zayne's First Birthday and Baptism.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On this day, I arrived home from <a href="/life/trips/usa">USA</a> and headed straight to mum's to get ready for <a href="/life/events/2023/zayne-bday-1">Zayne's First Birthday and Baptism</a>. </p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Zayne" src="/assets/images/zayne1-2fa02b8a2368813f24431c87668e431f.png" width="3130" height="1297" class="img_ev3q">
Zayne, my littlest love.</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
</feed>