<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog</id>
    <title>Carly.cool Blog</title>
    <updated>2023-07-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Carly.cool Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://coolcarly.github.io/img/my-icon-favicon.ico</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Office critique]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/25/2023-07/</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/25/2023-07/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Currently I am writing my thesis and subsequent manuscripts. I have so many emotions towards finishing my PhD.  At times I am really enjoying writing, and at other times I just want it all to finish. But the thought of finishing my PhD gives me a lot of anxiety, as this is all I've known for a long time. I fear that I will be terrible at any job I get in the future. Right now, I justify my work as "I am just a student", I am learning. What if, when I finish my PhD, I can't find anything that I am good at? What if I can't find a job that I like? This really scares me and I often worry about it.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Currently I am writing my thesis and subsequent manuscripts. I have so many emotions towards finishing my PhD.  At times I am really enjoying writing, and at other times I just want it all to finish. But the thought of finishing my PhD gives me a lot of anxiety, as this is all I've known for a long time. I fear that I will be terrible at any job I get in the future. Right now, I justify my work as "I am just a student", I am learning. What if, when I finish my PhD, I can't find anything that I am good at? What if I can't find a job that I like? This really scares me and I often worry about it. </p><p>At 9 am this morning, I had a meeting with my supervisors, Pawel and David to talk about my long awaited, first manuscript. We spoke about the structure and story of the research paper, and their feedback was very helpful. I'm kicking myself that I didn't show them sooner and push for this to be published 2 years ago (when the work was originally done).</p><p>During this meeting, I didn't realise that I was figgeting a lot. I was playing with my hair, biting my nails, moving around and just sitting very casually. Afterwards, Pawel pointed it out, and I was really embarrassed. I am glad that he said something to me though, because I feel like in future meetings I can pay closer attention to it. </p><p>In my defense though, my PhD feels very casual. I feel like my supervisors are my family; but maybe I am taking my comfort for granted. I also feel like it is not my work place. I am not treated like a staff member, nor do I get the same treatment as a staff member. </p><p>I went home after the meeting feeling really embarrased and a bit upset. To be honest, at the moment, I don't like certain things about myself; like my current connection with friends or my behaviour when I am stressed or anxious. I feel like I've spent a lot of time complaining about things and blaming others for my bad attitude. I need to retake control of my actions, stop complaining and just get stuff done. </p><p>I worked through comments for the rest of the day and then around 4 pm, I decided to go out for a run. Running has always helped me cope with my anxiety. I ran 10 km - which is the most I've ran since the marathon back in July 2022. My mood significantly improved since the run; however, not long after, I started to feel a bit sad. I want things to change. I want to be better.</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Date night]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/23/2023-07/</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/23/2023-07/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last night, Nick and I went to the movies to watch Oppenheimer, followed by dinner at Din Tai Fung in Miranda. The movie was really good, it told the story of Robert J Oppenheimer, a theoretical phyicist who helped to build the atomic bomb. I read some other reviews online. They say that Christopher Nolan got a lot of the biography right, with only a little bit of dramatisation.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last night, Nick and I went to the movies to watch Oppenheimer, followed by dinner at Din Tai Fung in Miranda. The movie was really good, it told the story of Robert J Oppenheimer, a theoretical phyicist who helped to build the atomic bomb. I read some other reviews online. They say that Christopher Nolan got a lot of the biography right, with only a little bit of dramatisation. </p><p>We sat on the beds at the front of the cinema. It was so comfortable and I was so happy that we chose those seats because it was a 3 hour movie! The alternative seating would've been wildly uncomfortable. </p><p>Dinner afterwards was also really great. We had dumplings and steamed buns! Yummy. </p><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/dumplings-buns-3e28292d534284e77a7f98dc5ba26e79.jpeg" width="40%" class="centered-image img_ev3q">]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My shoulder]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/17/2023-07/</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/17/2023-07/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An update on my shoulder: On 31 May, I fell off my paddle board and hit the right side of my body on the ground (the waves were very dumping at NW beach). As a result, I could barely move my arm or shoulder. As of last week, my shoulder was not in good shape - even after 5 weeks! Last week, I went for an xray. The doctor says that there may be some form of a fracture in my scapula bone. She requested that I get a CT scan. The CT scan confirmed that I have a fracture of the acromion. To my luck though, it is not located in the joint, nor does it affect the joint. Now it's just a waiting game to heal.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An update on my shoulder: On 31 May, I fell off my paddle board and hit the right side of my body on the ground (the waves were very dumping at NW beach). As a result, I could barely move my arm or shoulder. As of last week, my shoulder was not in good shape - even after 5 weeks! Last week, I went for an xray. The doctor says that there may be some form of a fracture in my scapula bone. She requested that I get a CT scan. The CT scan confirmed that I have a fracture of the acromion. To my luck though, it is not located in the joint, nor does it affect the joint. Now it's just a waiting game to heal.</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Update]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/16/2023-07/</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/16/2023-07/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-16T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's been really busy lately. For my PhD, I have been doing a lot of Raman Spectroscopy to characterise my materials in my project. I have also been writing a manuscript. Finally, on Friday, I submitted the manuscipt to my supervisors.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It's been really busy lately. For my PhD, I have been doing a lot of Raman Spectroscopy to characterise my materials in my project. I have also been writing a manuscript. Finally, on Friday, I submitted the manuscipt to my supervisors. </p><p>I am feeling nervous about the manuscript, and that they will not read it. Only last Thursday, David asked me about a manuscript. I told him it was on the way. So hopefully, since I've sent it through, they will all read it and give me helpful feedback. </p><p>In other news, I've been practicing surfing only a little. Yesterday, I stood up consistently for waves. My shoulder still hurts but it is getting better, slowly. </p><p>New posts: </p><ul><li><a href="/life/food-and-drink/craft-beer/illawarra/priciple-brewing">Principle Brewing</a></li><li><a href="/life/food-and-drink/cooking/mediterranian-bowl">Mediterranian Bowl</a></li><li><a href="/life/food-and-drink/cooking/west-african-peanut-soup">West African Peanut Soup</a></li></ul><p>Also, a long awaited comment bar has now been introduced into each side-bar home.</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[History of carly.cool]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/06/2023-07/</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/06/2023-07/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are live with the new website!]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We are live with the new website! </p><p>Let's not forget how the homepage looked just yesterday!</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="The first homepage of carly.cool" src="/assets/images/version1-website-701117e0af7c74607570009258cf9c9b.png" width="1418" height="1253" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Website!]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/new-website</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/new-website"/>
        <updated>2023-07-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Now, Carly.cool runs using Docusaurus.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Now, Carly.cool runs using Docusaurus.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Carly Baker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Roosters vs. Raiders NRL game]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/06/25/2023-06/</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/06/25/2023-06/"/>
        <updated>2023-06-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[football]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" alt="football" src="/assets/images/food-football-bde9470f49847f8ce4e5303100d15759.png" width="2044" height="939" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Roosters vs. Raiders game. Nick's dad had 4 spare corporate box tickets. Nick invited Nathan and Emma to come with us.</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Back to reality]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/06/26/2023-06/</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/06/26/2023-06/"/>
        <updated>2023-06-26T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[chip on a beenbag]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" alt="chip on a beenbag" src="/assets/images/chip-on-beenbag-2a02c87067f687f6c010ca68a6bbcdb7.png" width="3419" height="1475" class="img_ev3q">
Standard Monday workday. I feel too tired to go to the lab. I decided to work from home. All day, I have not done any thesis writing for my PhD , only updating my blog. I feel very nervous to go into the lab tomorrow. My supervisors want me to go to NZLD to do some lab work. After my trip to <a href="/life/trips/usa">USA 2023</a>, I don't want to go anywhere for the rest of the year. It is too windy to do any outside activities but I am feeling stressed from my lack of water time - swimming or paddling.</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zayne's 1st birthday & Baptism]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/06/24/2023-06/</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/06/24/2023-06/"/>
        <updated>2023-06-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On this day, I arrived home from USA and headed straight to mum's to get ready for Zayne's First Birthday and Baptism.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On this day, I arrived home from <a href="/life/trips/usa">USA</a> and headed straight to mum's to get ready for <a href="/life/events/2023/zayne-bday-1">Zayne's First Birthday and Baptism</a>. </p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Zayne" src="/assets/images/zayne1-2fa02b8a2368813f24431c87668e431f.png" width="3130" height="1297" class="img_ev3q">
Zayne, my littlest love.</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hardly working]]></title>
        <id>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/02/25/2023-02/</id>
        <link href="https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/02/25/2023-02/"/>
        <updated>2023-02-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hardly working]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Hardly working" src="/assets/images/hardly-working-f6a45b1113ab407f92157965980c2bdf.png" width="3355" height="1415" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>My day=trying to write but just cuddling with Chip.</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
</feed>