<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Carly.cool Blog</title>
        <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog</link>
        <description>Carly.cool Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exploration of bread making]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2024/May/bread</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2024/May/bread</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[9.5.2024]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>9.5.2024</em> <br>
Over the past few weeks, I have had the desire to improve my baking skills, so I have invested time into making a perfect loaf of bread. With every small tweak in a recipe, I realised that there are dramatic changes, which motivated me to write about the changes in bread quality in relation to the chemistry. </p><p>Flour contains proteins glutenin and gliadin, which combine in the presence of water to form gluten (Fig 1). Prior to the addition of water, glutenin exists as a colloid. Upon addition of water to the flour, the chains are allowed to stretch, seperate, and form new disulfide linkages. These disulfide linkages create a network of glutenin polymer that produces the strength and elasticity of bread dough. At the same time, the smaller gliadin proteins will disperse through the glutenin polymer network, which allows the bread to "rise". Thus, the gluten content in bread is attributed to the type of flour that is used to make the bread. </p><table><thead><tr><th align="center"><img loading="lazy" alt="Schematic of gluten formation" src="/assets/images/bread_schematic-2d7f68f1f1f8c5e36c0a766763aedc22.jpeg" width="1280" height="453" class="img_ev3q"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="center"><em>Fig 1. Schematic of gluten formation</em></td></tr></tbody></table><p>Mixing and kneading of the flour/water mixture encourages the gluten network to further develop. During this process, carbon dioxide is incorporated, producing a more porous dough once it is baked. Yet, we dont want the gluten networks to be so strong that they become chewy and tough. This is the reason that people turn to a "no-knead" method. Sometimes, a high water content is enough to facilitate formation of strong gluten networks. </p><p>Yet, there is one more ingredient that is required to create the gluten network... and that is salt. As mentioned in the <a href="/science/salt">"salting-out"</a> post, salt helps to decrease the water content. In this instance, salt will remove water from the protein/polymer network to increase the strength and elasicity. </p><hr><p>The initial recipe that I started with came from Nagi: <a href="https://www.recipetineats.com/easy-yeast-bread-recipe-no-knead/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">RecipeTinEats</a>.</p><p>First, I started off with a "no kneading" approach to bread making. Following the recipe exactly. In my first attempt, I did activate the yeast in warm water, using only 1 packet mixture (7 g). In the end, the bread was very tough to cut and very and very dense. But it was still quite tasty. These bread flavours arise from fermentation. The high bread density is possibly attributed to a low water content. Thus, instead of using "cups" measurement, I went for weighing out the ingredients using a scale. </p><p>A few days later, I used the recommended amount of yeast (2 tsp), weighed out the flour (450 g to be exact) and the water. I saw that the dough was still a bit "doughy", so I added an extra 20 mL of water to the batch. It was too sticky to be able to knead (Fig 2, img1), yet it felt very soft and after allowing it to rise for several hours, I baked it using the dutch oven. NOTE: I was sure that it had risen well, when the dough was very bubbly on the surface and small movements of the bowl containing the dough resulted in a "jiggling" of the dough surface. This time, it rose more than the previous batch (likely due to the extra yeast) and was less dense than the last batch (owing to the excess water added).</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="second batch" src="/assets/images/bread2-19d89ba343b4abe8ec1492f13ad64569.jpeg" width="1280" height="416" class="img_ev3q">
<em>Fig 2. Batch 2: (img 1) sticky dough, (img 2) moulded dough for baking, (img 3) final product.</em> <br></p><p>There were other things I wanted to explore. For instance, what is the impact of leaving the dough to sit for longer? What is the impact of kneading? Therefore, the next batch that I made, was using the same contents as above only, I allowed the dough to sit for 3 hours at room temperature, then 2 days in the fridge (covered). The day before cooking, I pulled out the dough, moulded it into a ball and allowed it to sit covered in the fridge overnight. When I baked this loaf, it rose slightly more than the last batch, but was more porous as well (Fig 3). From what I understand, it seems that when you put the dough in the fridge, fermentation is slowed down to allow the development of more complex flavours.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="third batch" src="/assets/images/bread-3-688d4025dcac098afd75278bf7cd9fd2.jpeg" width="1280" height="637" class="img_ev3q">
<em>Fig 3. Batch 3: (img 1) moulded dough for baking, (img 2) final product and (img 3) a photo of the sliced bread, observing the porosity of the loaf.</em> <br></p><p><em>15.5.2024</em> <br></p><p>The next parameter that I wanted to test is the impact of kneading on the dough. Therefore, a dough was prepared as previous, however, it was kneaded for 5 minutes of before allowing the dough to rise. Due to the better properties of the previous batch of bread, the dough was immediately placed in the fridge, in a covered bowel. The dough was left for close to 22 hours in the fridge. When I was ready to bake the bread, it appeared to have similar textures as the previous batch, however, was less soft.  </p><p>The dough was moulded and scored (using tips that I got from <a href="https://vegpatchkitchen.co.uk/what-is-oven-spring/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">vegpatchkitchen</a>) and baked from it's cold state. The idea behind scoring is that it allows the gases to uniformly escape, making bread the rise more uniform, instead of having that weird bubble in the middle of the loaf (as seen in img 2 of Fig 3).</p><p>While the final bread loaf in Fig 4 (img 3) appears to be more uniform, without the ugly bubble in the middle, it was less porous than batch 3 (Fig 3). This was attributed to the small additions of flour that I added in order to knead the bread. As small amounts of excess flour decreases the water content, the bread ultimately became more dense. I thought this bread was the tastiest and best looking so far. </p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="fourth batch" src="/assets/images/bread4-c1294227c25e4d5f5ce68565394cd866.jpeg" width="1280" height="427" class="img_ev3q">
<em>Fig 4. Batch 4: (img 1) dough after kneading and ready to be placed in the frige, (img 2) moulded dough for baking, (img 3) final product and (img 4) a photo of the sliced bread, observing the porosity of the loaf.</em></p><p><em>20.5.2024</em> <br></p><p>This time, I doubled the batch size using the following ingredients:</p><p align="center"> 900 g bread flour <br> 656 g warm water (~ 40°C) <br> 4 tsp salt <br> 4 tsp of yeast</p><p>In this batch, the process was as follows. First, 4 tsp of dried yeast was added to 2 cups of warm water (equivalent to 427 g of water). The yeast was allowed to grow for 5 minutes and then added to the flour/salt mixture. The mixture was combined with a wooden spoon. As it appeared to be very flaky and floury, an extra 229 g of water was added. It appeared to be very slicky and slimy. It was too sticky to be kneaded, or even handled. This large batch was left in the mixing bowl, covered and put straight into the fridge for 22 hours. </p><p>The oven was preheated to 220°C and the dutch oven was preheated for 30 minutes. During this time, half of the mixture was taken from the large mixing bowl, moulded and scored and put back in the fridge (covered) until it was ready to bake it. The dough (on the baking paper) was gently placed into the dutch oven and baked for 30 mins with the lid on, and a further 10 mins with the lid off. </p><p>The bread was probably the best that I have made so far (I know I say this everytime... but is true). The defining features were the high porosity caused by the high water content, the uniform growth in the dough due to scoring of the loaf and the softness of the inside! </p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="fifth batch" src="/assets/images/bread5-2f25c7674ba79a4c29f3031a018b639a.jpeg" width="1280" height="429" class="img_ev3q">
<em>Fig 5. Batch 5. (img 1) risen dough, (img 2) scored dough, (img 3) baked bread out of the oven and (img 4) image of the face of the bread, showing a higher level of porosity.</em></p><p>Now... The second half of the mixture will sit in the fridge for a few more days, and I will bake and observe the difference. Stay tuned!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>baking</category>
            <category>bread</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Inductively Coupled Plasma (ICP) mass spectrometry (MS)/Optical emission spectroscopy (OES)]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2024/May/icp_</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2024/May/icp_</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Recently I started a position as a lab technician with Australian National Fabrication Facility (ANFF). One of the requirements of this position is to maintain the ICP. Therefore, I decided to write a short post here about ICP, which I will update with the various things that I have learned along the way.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Recently I started a position as a lab technician with Australian National Fabrication Facility (ANFF). One of the requirements of this position is to maintain the ICP. Therefore, I decided to write a short post here about ICP, which I will update with the various things that I have learned along the way. </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-is-icp">What is ICP?<a href="#what-is-icp" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What is ICP?" title="Direct link to What is ICP?">​</a></h2><p>Inductively coupled plasma (ICP) mass spectrometry (MS) or optical emission spectroscopy (OES) is a method of elemental analysis which utilises a plasma source. In ICP-MS, the ions are directly measured. In contract, ICP-OES uses an optical spectrometer to measure the photons emitted as they pass through the plasma. While both methods are extremely fast to use, cheap and straightforward, the ICP-OES has a higher sensitivity to detection. </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="how-does-icp-work">How does ICP work?<a href="#how-does-icp-work" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to How does ICP work?" title="Direct link to How does ICP work?">​</a></h2><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Schematic of ICP" src="/assets/images/fig1-icp-b973c0fd8a33d264862421400b87c4e1.jpeg" width="1280" height="462" class="img_ev3q"></p><p> Figure 1. Schematic of ICP: (a) engineered setup and (b) behaviour of the sample inside the sample channel. Images taken from (Hou and Jones) and(McCurdy and Potter) </p><p>A schematic of an ICP is displayed in Fig 1. The liquid sample is injected into a spray chamber which is converted to an aerosol via a nebuliser. During this process, only the very fine particles are injected into the inductor. In the inductor, the sample aerosol is further dried and vapourised due to the high temperatures (10000 K) in the sample carrier. In this process, all chemical bonds are broken, allowing for the vapourisation of each individual atom (Fig 1b). The free atoms collide with plasma, allowing them to transition to an excited state. Upon relaxation to ground state, the ions/atoms will emit a photon of characteristic energies, which can be used to determine the elemental origin of the ions. The total number of photons emitted is proportional to the concentration.</p><p>The ionisation plasma is typically argon gas as it is chemically inert and contains a high proportion of cations and electrons with a high electron density. In the set up shown in Fig 1a, radiofrequency (RF) is applied to a coil which produces “seed” electrons which are accelerated and collide with argon gas to form argon plasma and electrons:
Ar(g) → Ar<sup>+</sup> + e<sup>-</sup></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="about-sample-preparation">About sample preparation<a href="#about-sample-preparation" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to About sample preparation" title="Direct link to About sample preparation">​</a></h2><p>Solubilised solutions (aqueous or organic) are required to perform ICP analysis. Therefore, samples (&lt;0.2 %&gt;) are typically treated with nitric acid (HNO<sub>3</sub>) or HCl, in a process referred to as "acid digestion".  Sample concentrations of &lt;0.2% are crucial to avoid any matrix effects.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="matrix-effects">Matrix effects<a href="#matrix-effects" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Matrix effects" title="Direct link to Matrix effects">​</a></h2><p>Matrix effects are interferences in the analysis due ton signal dift caused by the deposition of solids on the sample apertures or signal suppression caused by salt ions. The typical salt interference is caused by oxide formation, which seems to reduce the ion flow and promotes clogging at the sample cone (the interface that analyses ion extraction). With years of research, matrix effects have typically solved through the use of OES compared to MS. ICP-OES relies on photon emission rather than ion acceleration, which makes it less susceptible to interferences. </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="advantages-of-icp-compared-to-other-elemental-analyses">Advantages of ICP compared to other elemental analyses<a href="#advantages-of-icp-compared-to-other-elemental-analyses" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Advantages of ICP compared to other elemental analyses" title="Direct link to Advantages of ICP compared to other elemental analyses">​</a></h2><p>As ICP heats to very high temperatures, samples undergo more efficient vaporisation, atomisation and excitation. This allows for a wider range of elements to be analysed by ICP. In addition, the high temperature means that there is less water vapour present, in turn reducing the concentration of oxygen species and thus a lower level of matrix interferences caused by oxide formation. </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="references">References<a href="#references" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to References" title="Direct link to References">​</a></h2><ol><li>Ammann, A.A., Inductively coupled plasma mass spectrometry (ICP MS): a versatile tool. Journal of Mass Spectrometry, 2007. 42(4): p. 419-427.<br></li><li>Hou, X. and B.T. Jones, Inductively Coupled Plasma Optical Emission Spectrometry, in Encyclopedia of Analytical Chemistry. 2000, John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd: Chichester. p. 9468-6485.<br></li><li>McCurdy, E. and D. Potter, Optimising ICP-MS for the determination of trace metals in high matrix samples. Spectroscopy Europe, 2001. 13: p. 14+16-20.<br></li><li>Kopru, S. and M. Soylak, Inductively coupled plasma-mass spectrometry (ICP-MS) detection of trace metal contents of children cosmetics. Optical and Quantum Electronics, 2024. 56(3): p. 399.</li></ol>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Almost there]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/12/15/2023-12/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/12/15/2023-12/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[It's been just over a month since I've wrote something in my blog.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It's been just over a month since I've wrote something in my blog. </p><p>For the last month and a half, I have been working through the comments that I received back. It's been a real tough time, because there were a lot of comments. I honestly felt like everything I knew about my topic was wrong. I have been reading so much and redoing all my figures/analyses. Each day, I started work at 7 am and continued until 10 pm. I even spent all my weekends working on it. Until finally, I felt proud of my thesis! Now, it is being reviewed by one of my supervisors. </p><p>The plan now is to write a couple of research papers. However, my current dilemma is that I dont want to write a paper if my supervisors do not agree with what I wrote in my thesis.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>PhD</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Updates]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/10/31/2023-10/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/10/31/2023-10/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Over the weekend, Nick and I headed to the Hunter Valley for a wedding. It was great to get away, and now I am feeling fresh to resume writing.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over the weekend, Nick and I headed to the <a href="/life/trips/hunter-valley">Hunter Valley</a> for a wedding. It was great to get away, and now I am feeling fresh to resume writing.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PhD update]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/10/25/2023-10/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/10/25/2023-10/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[- [x] As it stands, I have completed writing my PhD thesis. Below is a table summary of the chapters, with type of chapter, number of words (in total, incl. references, and figures) and number of pages]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul class="contains-task-list containsTaskList_mC6p"><li class="task-list-item"><input type="checkbox" checked="" disabled=""> <!-- -->As it stands, I have completed writing my PhD thesis. Below is a table summary of the chapters, with type of chapter, number of words (in total, incl. references, and figures) and number of pages</li><li class="task-list-item"><input type="checkbox" disabled=""> <!-- -->I still have a few more experiments to conduct for Research Chapter 5 and 7. </li><li class="task-list-item"><input type="checkbox" disabled=""> <!-- -->I still need to write up the supporting information (which will be a lot)</li><li class="task-list-item"><input type="checkbox" disabled=""> <!-- -->I still need to write papers. </li><li class="task-list-item"><input type="checkbox" disabled=""> <!-- -->I plan to complete my thesis and send by Friday 27 Oct. </li></ul><h5 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="table-summary-of-my-phd-thesis">Table Summary of my PhD thesis:<a href="#table-summary-of-my-phd-thesis" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Table Summary of my PhD thesis:" title="Direct link to Table Summary of my PhD thesis:">​</a></h5><table><thead><tr><th align="left">Chapter</th><th align="center">Content</th><th align="center">Words</th><th align="right">Pages</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left">1</td><td align="center">Intro</td><td align="center">11937</td><td align="right">36</td></tr><tr><td align="left">2</td><td align="center">Methods</td><td align="center">9150</td><td align="right">27</td></tr><tr><td align="left">3</td><td align="center">Research</td><td align="center">6289</td><td align="right">29</td></tr><tr><td align="left">4</td><td align="center">Research</td><td align="center">11257</td><td align="right">39</td></tr><tr><td align="left">5</td><td align="center">Research</td><td align="center">6351</td><td align="right">27</td></tr><tr><td align="left">6</td><td align="center">Research</td><td align="center">6887</td><td align="right">24</td></tr><tr><td align="left">7</td><td align="center">Research</td><td align="center">9908</td><td align="right">34</td></tr><tr><td align="left">8</td><td align="center">Conclusions</td><td align="center">3700</td><td align="right">11</td></tr><tr><td align="left">Total</td><td align="center"></td><td align="center">65479</td><td align="right">227</td></tr></tbody></table>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[More content]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/10/22/2023-10/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/10/22/2023-10/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A few updates include:]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A few updates include: </p><ul><li><a href="/phd/tips-for-writing">Tips for writing</a> in PhD section</li><li><a href="/life/surf-lifesaving/patrol-days">Recap of patrol</a> in Life section / Surf Lifesaving</li><li><a href="/phd/pros-cons">Pros and cons for starting a PhD</a> in PhD section</li><li>Added <a href="/life/food-and-drink/restaurants-and-bars/rocksalt-menai">Rock Salt, Menai</a> to Life section / Food and drink / Restaurants and bars</li><li>Added <a href="/life/trips/hunter-valley">Trips to the Hunter Valley</a> to Life section / Trips</li></ul>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Another Saturday]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/10/21/2023-10/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/10/21/2023-10/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Updates:]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Updates:</p><ol><li><a href="/phd/conferences/polynsw">Lessons from my PhD</a></li><li><a href="/phd/conferences/polynsw">PolyNSW</a> </li><li><a href="/phd/starting-over-a-phd">If I could start my PhD again</a></li></ol>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Some days are productive, some days are not]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/08/25/2023-08/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/08/25/2023-08/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Last Thursday, my supervisor cancelled my weekly PhD meeting and instead requested that we sit down and go through my thesis and decide what we need to do moving forward. Both Pawel and David agreed that I should not be doing anymore lab work and just focus on writing my thesis! There it is "only focus on writing".]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last Thursday, my supervisor cancelled my weekly PhD meeting and instead requested that we sit down and go through my thesis and decide what we need to do moving forward. Both Pawel and David agreed that I should not be doing anymore lab work and just focus on writing my thesis! There it is "only focus on writing". </p><p><em>Productivity:</em> From Friday onwards, I started writing all my results down. I wrote a lot in the span of 4 days and I felt that if I kept writing then I could be finished by the end of the month. </p><p><em>Unproductive:</em> On Wednesday 23 August, I had a really bad day of writing. By 3 pm, I was on the lounge watching a TV show. I did not attempt to recommence writing for the rest of the evening. It really messed me around on Thursday. At this rate, I won't finish my PhD in time!</p><p><em>A tip to improve productivity:</em> I was lucky this week in my Thursday meeting. I got a few tips from my supervisors about writing. David commented that the best thing to do when you are not feeling like thinking is to write out the methods chapter. He was right. Writing out my methods chapter is a simple way to get myself in the mood of writing and to continue my writing routine. </p><p><em>More unproductivity:</em> This morning, I went driving around Wollongong to try and get a quote to fix my passenger-side mirror of my car. Grant from Fernhill Smash Repairs told me that he would be in touch later in the afternoon. NOTE: the passenger side-mirror is no longer afixed to the car as I nipped it off on the way home from the beach yesterday. Without a passenger side-mirror, I cannot drive my car. This means that I can't drive to North Wollongong beach! I need to paddle in the morning for me to feel fresh for a day of writing! This screwed up my whole day. At 10 am, I gave up on writing and decided to head to Innovation Campus to get some data off the computers. I ran there and remained until 4 pm..... and that is all I did today.</p><p>In the evening, Nick and I walked to <a href="/life/food-and-drink/craft-beer/illawarra/barrel-shephard">The Barrel Shephard</a> for dinner and drinks. I felt aweful, like I didn't deserve to be going out after a day of very little work and progress. Note to future self: stop going into the lab, save it for the weekend or afternoons.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A very stupid thing]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/08/08/2023-08/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/08/08/2023-08/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[When I woke up at 5.55 am, it seemed like it was going to be another cracker of a day. I prepared for teaching, went for a run, did some stretching and showered all before 8.30 am. I was more than ready to make huge progress today!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When I woke up at 5.55 am, it seemed like it was going to be another cracker of a day. I prepared for teaching, went for a run, did some stretching and showered all before 8.30 am. I was more than ready to make huge progress today! </p><p>I arrived at work at 9 am and from the minute I began to do things in the lab, everything went wrong. I couldn't get any good data. Around 10 am, I went to get help to fix a cable for my potentiostat (as the wires lost connection to reduce the signal). However, I was unsuccessful in getting help. A colleague/researcher said to meet her at 3 pm to repair the cable; but I couldnt wait this long as I was due to teach at 1.30 til 4.30 pm (Week 3 of Semester 2).. </p><p>By this point it was 11 am - I was feeling really tired and unmotivated. </p><p>My first thought was to go home. I lost motivation when I realised that I would only be home for 1 hour before having to leave again. Instead, I pulled out my soft back warmer from my draw and used it as a pillow. I put my head down on the desk and had an hour nap. </p><p>I woke up less tired than before, but really groggy. I packed my safety glasses and water bottle into my handbag and walked towards my car, then drove to the main campus. Travel between the innovation campus and the main campus is really tedious and it is often difficult to find parking in the middle of the day. </p><p>I was parked and ready to get out of the car at 1 pm. I walked towards Panzinis, a cafe located in front of the UOW library. I go here for coffee because they offer staff discounts and I love discouts! I ordered my coffee and it was made within 5 minutes. It was a rather pleasant experience - too bad that I was not in a good mood. </p><p>The undergraduate chemistry labs are located in building 21 on level 3. I headed here after I was handed my coffee - but I was at least 20 minutes early. When I walked into the lab, it was empty abar one demonstrator - Sue. I chatted for less than a minute before rereading over my emails that said I was only rostered for Week 9. In sheer disbelief, I spent a few minutes researching my emails and was convinced that I showed up for no reason! In embarrassment, I left and drove to North Wollongong beach. "Wow" I thought. "How stupid". "Why didn't I read my emails?" </p><p>I was pretty relieved though, because I didn't really want to teach. I don't need the extra funds that bad and it's not worth taking time away from my writing. Excited that I could fix the potentiostat, I also sent an email to a colleague, indicating my error and that I would be there at 3 pm. </p><p>Just as I was about to get out of my car and go for a dip in the ocean to calm down my anxiety and embarrassment, I received an email from Giel (the subject coordinator) who asked me to come back because I was rostered to work. Can you believe how embarrassed I was after this? It took me 15 minutes to return, park and walk to the labs. I quickly walked into the service room, dodging the lines of students waiting to collect a pH probe for their experiment. I threw on a red lab coat, my safety glasses and grabbed a pen. </p><p>I apologised several times to Giel and I literally felt like slapping my forehead because it was such a stupid thing that happened. The worst thing though, was sending a third email to my colleague telling her that I was wrong and I was meant to teach! </p><p>The labs were very slow and very basic. The students were working on acid-base titrations. In that moment, I thought that it wasn't too bad. I actually enjoyed it.  I'm just glad that I don't have to teach all the time. The labs ended at 4.30 pm. I drove straight home and relaxed until dinner time. </p><p>I honestly feel like I wasted the whole day.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rewarding myself]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/08/04/2023-08/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/08/04/2023-08/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Lately, I have been freaking out with the amount of work still left in my PhD. Today, I had planned to have a writing day but I realised as I opened various thesis chapters, that I have actually written a lot! At 11 am, I decided to head into the lab to try to resynthesise a monomer for my second research chapter. While searching the freezer for my materials, I came across a molecule that I had synthesised previously, but never used. It was a dibromo-compound that was initially synthesised for a grignard reaction.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lately, I have been freaking out with the amount of work still left in my PhD. Today, I had planned to have a writing day but I realised as I opened various thesis chapters, that I have actually written a lot! At 11 am, I decided to head into the lab to try to resynthesise a monomer for my second research chapter. While searching the freezer for my materials, I came across a molecule that I had synthesised previously, but never used. It was a dibromo-compound that was initially synthesised for a grignard reaction. </p><p>For fun, I set up a 1 mL (200 mg) scale <a href="/science/polymer-science/synthesis/darp">direct arylation polymerisation</a>. For the rest of the day, I felt so happy and accomplished. I feel so excited to work this polymer up and characterise it. </p><p>To hear more about this, and see the fun I have with these reactions, visit <a href="/phd/side-projects">side projects</a>. </p><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/dhap-461e005e73beee5a4a5377372feae3c5.jpeg" width="60%" class="centered-image img_ev3q">]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Garlic & Rosemary Pull apart bread]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/08/02/2023-08/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/08/02/2023-08/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[It's already August! Wow, where has the time gone? Five months left until I need to submit my PhD thesis.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It's already August! Wow, where has the time gone? Five months left until I need to submit my PhD thesis. </p><p>I arrived home from work after an unsuccessful day in the lab. The electrodes attached to my potentiostat were disfunctioning. I spent my 3 hours of lab time, trying to trouble shoot the problem. With the help of one of the guys in the workshop, I was able to fix the electrode. However, upon a "dummy test", the signal was not strong. I gave up, and decided to go home and not waste anymore time. </p><p>I arrived home and prepared a quiche for dinner. I was feeling inspired by Emma (as over the weekend, she made a really awesome scrambled eggs). The egg filling alone contained some butter and rosemary. </p><p>After I finished preparing dinner, I was still in the mood to cook - anything to avoid working on my thesis! I decided to prepare tomorrow nights dinner as well. </p><p>I don't know about you, but I get tired of eating similar things all the time. I feel like it is super boring and not creative at all. While I was having these thoughts, I had finished the rest of our loaf of bread. That's when I was inspired to make some bread. </p><p>I remember when I was much younger, around 15 years old and would often bake various things for my family. I enjoyed baking a lot - from bread to cakes. However, I saw so many people around me who were a lot better. I often compared myself to others and it really demotivated me to cook (Yes, I always wanted to be the best). I wonder what life would have been like if I didn't compare myself and just did the things that I enjoyed - because I enjoyed them. </p><p>Maybe my enjoyment of baking and "creative cooking" is the reason that I chose chemistry. I always wonder what drove me to stay in chemistry. I usually say that it was because I got the best marks for the least amount of effort - which is probably true. Now, I am thinking that it was also because I was using my hands to create something. Synthesis is very similar to cooking: a step by step process to create something wonderful. </p><p>The funny thing is though, I struggle so much to follow recipes. The same thing applies in the lab: I struggle a lot to follow new synthetic protocols. This caused so much stress during my undergrad: as I didn't perform as well as some of the other students. Somehow I have made it through and am almost finished a PhD in chemistry! Sometimes I forget how amazing it is that I've made it this far. Dani had to remind me earlier today when we were discussing my PhD. </p><p>Anyway, the <a href="https://sallysbakingaddiction.com/rosemary-garlic-pull-apart-bread/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Garlic &amp; Rosemary pull apart bread</a> that I made was taken from Sally's baking addiction. There is some good stuff on her blog! I also listed the procedure that I used (because I never follow a procedure well and there are always things that I modify or change) in my <a href="/life/food-and-drink/cooking/pull-apart-bread">Pull-apart bread</a> post. </p><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/garlic-rosemary-bread-22e55f4fb8219f5ec83cee62fce49026.jpeg" width="50%" class="centered-image img_ev3q">]]></content:encoded>
            <category>cooking</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Changing my attitude]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/28/2023-07/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/28/2023-07/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[It didn't take long to change my attitude once I acknowledged it.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It didn't take long to change my attitude once I acknowledged it. </p><p>Over the last few days, I have had time to reflect on my actions and my feelings and I realised that I need to be kinder to myself and try to think of "criticism" as "feedback". My Supervisors have 50 years of experience over me, so I need to stop comparing myself to other people. Instead, I need to compare myself from the start of my PhD to myself now. I am very proud of how much I've grown as a person and a scientist. </p><p>My feelings of doom have become more optimistic as I feel excited to finish and get a job in the real world! It's funny how a little bit of perspective can make the world around you seem more positive. </p><p>This weekend, I am taking a break and we are heading up to Terrigal for Emma's 30th birthday and Hens weekend! Should be good.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Office critique]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/25/2023-07/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/25/2023-07/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Currently I am writing my thesis and subsequent manuscripts. I have so many emotions towards finishing my PhD.  At times I am really enjoying writing, and at other times I just want it all to finish. But the thought of finishing my PhD gives me a lot of anxiety, as this is all I've known for a long time. I fear that I will be terrible at any job I get in the future. Right now, I justify my work as "I am just a student", I am learning. What if, when I finish my PhD, I can't find anything that I am good at? What if I can't find a job that I like? This really scares me and I often worry about it.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Currently I am writing my thesis and subsequent manuscripts. I have so many emotions towards finishing my PhD.  At times I am really enjoying writing, and at other times I just want it all to finish. But the thought of finishing my PhD gives me a lot of anxiety, as this is all I've known for a long time. I fear that I will be terrible at any job I get in the future. Right now, I justify my work as "I am just a student", I am learning. What if, when I finish my PhD, I can't find anything that I am good at? What if I can't find a job that I like? This really scares me and I often worry about it. </p><p>At 9 am this morning, I had a meeting with my supervisors, to talk about my long awaited, first manuscript. We spoke about the structure and story of the research paper, and their feedback was very helpful. I'm kicking myself that I didn't show them sooner and push for this to be published 2 years ago (when the work was originally done).</p><p>During this meeting, I didn't realise that I was figgeting a lot. I was playing with my hair, biting my nails, moving around and just sitting very casually. Afterwards, it was pointed it out, and I was really embarrassed. I am glad that he said something to me though, because I feel like in future meetings I can pay closer attention to it. </p><p>In my defense though, my PhD feels very casual. I feel like my supervisors are my family; but maybe I am taking my comfort for granted. I also feel like it is not my work place. I am not treated like a staff member, nor do I get the same treatment as a staff member. </p><p>I went home after the meeting feeling really embarrased and a bit upset. To be honest, at the moment, I don't like certain things about myself; like my current connection with friends or my behaviour when I am stressed or anxious. I feel like I've spent a lot of time complaining about things and blaming others for my bad attitude. I need to retake control of my actions, stop complaining and just get stuff done. </p><p>I worked through comments for the rest of the day and then around 4 pm, I decided to go out for a run. Running has always helped me cope with my anxiety. I ran 10 km - which is the most I've ran since the marathon back in July 2022. My mood significantly improved since the run; however, not long after, I started to feel a bit sad. I want things to change. I want to be better.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Date night]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/23/2023-07/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/23/2023-07/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Last night, Nick and I went to the movies to watch Oppenheimer, followed by dinner at Din Tai Fung in Miranda. The movie was really good, it told the story of Robert J Oppenheimer, a theoretical phyicist who helped to build the atomic bomb. I read some other reviews online. They say that Christopher Nolan got a lot of the biography right, with only a little bit of dramatisation.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last night, Nick and I went to the movies to watch Oppenheimer, followed by dinner at Din Tai Fung in Miranda. The movie was really good, it told the story of Robert J Oppenheimer, a theoretical phyicist who helped to build the atomic bomb. I read some other reviews online. They say that Christopher Nolan got a lot of the biography right, with only a little bit of dramatisation. </p><p>We sat on the beds at the front of the cinema. It was so comfortable and I was so happy that we chose those seats because it was a 3 hour movie! The alternative seating would've been wildly uncomfortable. </p><p>Dinner afterwards was also really great. We had dumplings and steamed buns! Yummy. </p><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/dumplings-buns-3e28292d534284e77a7f98dc5ba26e79.jpeg" width="40%" class="centered-image img_ev3q">]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My shoulder]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/17/2023-07/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/17/2023-07/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[An update on my shoulder: On 31 May, I fell off my paddle board and hit the right side of my body on the ground (the waves were very dumping at NW beach). As a result, I could barely move my arm or shoulder. As of last week, my shoulder was not in good shape - even after 5 weeks! Last week, I went for an xray. The doctor says that there may be some form of a fracture in my scapula bone. She requested that I get a CT scan. The CT scan confirmed that I have a fracture of the acromion. To my luck though, it is not located in the joint, nor does it affect the joint. Now it's just a waiting game to heal.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An update on my shoulder: On 31 May, I fell off my paddle board and hit the right side of my body on the ground (the waves were very dumping at NW beach). As a result, I could barely move my arm or shoulder. As of last week, my shoulder was not in good shape - even after 5 weeks! Last week, I went for an xray. The doctor says that there may be some form of a fracture in my scapula bone. She requested that I get a CT scan. The CT scan confirmed that I have a fracture of the acromion. To my luck though, it is not located in the joint, nor does it affect the joint. Now it's just a waiting game to heal.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Update]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/16/2023-07/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/16/2023-07/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[It's been really busy lately. For my PhD, I have been doing a lot of Raman Spectroscopy to characterise my materials in my project. I have also been writing a manuscript. Finally, on Friday, I submitted the manuscipt to my supervisors.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It's been really busy lately. For my PhD, I have been doing a lot of Raman Spectroscopy to characterise my materials in my project. I have also been writing a manuscript. Finally, on Friday, I submitted the manuscipt to my supervisors. </p><p>I am feeling nervous about the manuscript, and that they will not read it. Only last Thursday, David asked me about a manuscript. I told him it was on the way. So hopefully, since I've sent it through, they will all read it and give me helpful feedback. </p><p>In other news, I've been practicing surfing only a little. Yesterday, I stood up consistently for waves. My shoulder still hurts but it is getting better, slowly. </p><p>New posts: </p><ul><li><a href="/life/food-and-drink/craft-beer/illawarra/priciple-brewing">Principle Brewing</a></li><li><a href="/life/food-and-drink/cooking/mediterranian-bowl">Mediterranian Bowl</a></li><li><a href="/life/food-and-drink/cooking/west-african-peanut-soup">West African Peanut Soup</a></li></ul><p>Also, a long awaited comment bar has now been introduced into each side-bar home.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[History of carly.cool]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/06/2023-07/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/06/2023-07/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[We are live with the new website!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We are live with the new website! </p><p>Let's not forget how the homepage looked just yesterday!</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="The first homepage of carly.cool" src="/assets/images/version1-website-701117e0af7c74607570009258cf9c9b.png" width="1418" height="1253" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Website!]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/new-website</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/new-website</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Now, Carly.cool runs using Docusaurus.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Now, Carly.cool runs using Docusaurus.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Roosters vs. Raiders NRL game]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/06/25/2023-06/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/06/25/2023-06/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[football]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" alt="football" src="/assets/images/food-football-bde9470f49847f8ce4e5303100d15759.png" width="2044" height="939" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Roosters vs. Raiders game. Nick's dad had 4 spare corporate box tickets. Nick invited Nathan and Emma to come with us.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Back to reality]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/06/26/2023-06/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/06/26/2023-06/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[chip on a beenbag]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" alt="chip on a beenbag" src="/assets/images/chip-on-beenbag-2a02c87067f687f6c010ca68a6bbcdb7.png" width="3419" height="1475" class="img_ev3q">
Standard Monday workday. I feel too tired to go to the lab. I decided to work from home. All day, I have not done any thesis writing for my PhD , only updating my blog. I feel very nervous to go into the lab tomorrow. My supervisors want me to go to NZLD to do some lab work. After my trip to <a href="/life/trips/usa">USA 2023</a>, I don't want to go anywhere for the rest of the year. It is too windy to do any outside activities but I am feeling stressed from my lack of water time - swimming or paddling.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zayne's 1st birthday & Baptism]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/06/24/2023-06/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/06/24/2023-06/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[On this day, I arrived home from USA and headed straight to mum's to get ready for Zayne's First Birthday and Baptism.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On this day, I arrived home from <a href="/life/trips/usa">USA</a> and headed straight to mum's to get ready for <a href="/life/events/2023/zayne-bday-1">Zayne's First Birthday and Baptism</a>. </p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Zayne" src="/assets/images/zayne1-2fa02b8a2368813f24431c87668e431f.png" width="3130" height="1297" class="img_ev3q">
Zayne, my littlest love.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>