<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Carly.cool Blog</title>
        <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog</link>
        <description>Carly.cool Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yellow, Potts Point]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2025/05/13/2025/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2025/05/13/2025/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[It was early evening on Saturday 10th May when Nick and I caught the train from Jannali to Kings Cross. After a short 10 minute stroll down Darlinghurst road, which leads onto Macleay St, we arrived at Yellow. Yellow is a fine-dining vegan restaurant. They change their menu seasonally and try to develop meals based on what foods are available - therefore taking a more sustainable approach to dining.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It was early evening on Saturday 10th May when Nick and I caught the train from Jannali to Kings Cross. After a short 10 minute stroll down Darlinghurst road, which leads onto Macleay St, we arrived at Yellow. Yellow is a fine-dining vegan restaurant. They change their menu seasonally and try to develop meals based on what foods are available - therefore taking a more sustainable approach to dining. </p><p>Upon arrival, the waiter took my coat (how fancy) and sat us at a table next to a window. The atmosphere was pretty dark with low lights - giving an almost romantic vibe.It was also rather large, with two areas seperated by a narrow wall - seperating the dining from the bar. </p><p>From the minute we sat down, the waiters paid a lot of attention to us and our "needs". I say it like this, because it is not really a need, but more a want but I'm sure that you get the gist of what I am saying. </p><p>This dining experience consisted of a tasting menu with a wine pairing. Yes, you heard (read) it right, a tasting menu. We were served 11 (each) small bites of food which resulted in us leaving with full bellies (not too full, but just right). I've put the menu here: </p><table><thead><tr><th align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/yellow-70d88d774b7d2ecf0840c88f22dfa3b7.png" width="674" height="541" class="img_ev3q"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="center"><em>Image caption:</em> The menu at Yellow: Food (left) and wine pairing (right). We were not given the menu until the end of our sitting.</td></tr></tbody></table><p>Everything on this menu was amazing. I found that it was so artistic and creative. The cool thing was we were in there "blind". We did not know what we were going to eat until it was handed to us. After we paid and were ready to leave, the waiter gave us a take home copy of the menu. </p><p>In between the sunflower seed "risotto", and eggplant parcel, we were handed some sourdough bread with oil. This sourdough bread was very impressive. It was so fluffy and aerated, but the crust was also really crusty - easy to eat but not too hard. For sure the best sourdough bread I've ever had. </p><p>This was a pretty cool experience. But yes, it was expensive. Dining alone was $110 pp (not including the mushroom tacos circled in the menu above - an extra $9 pp for a bite size, think of a Captain's Table cracker). The wine pairing was also an additional $145 pp. I wont be going back anytime soon because of this reason. Yet, it was really amazing as I felt like I was apart of something spectacular.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Check out my new post!]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2025/check-out</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2025/check-out</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I've been pretty lousy with writing. Since I started work as a Researcher for the critical minerals hub in Sydney, I have been unmotivated to do writing for myself. At the moment, I am on leave for the Easter break. I took a little bit of rest and grasped some inspiration to write an article about tooth health. Check it out here:]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I've been pretty lousy with writing. Since I started work as a Researcher for the critical minerals hub in Sydney, I have been unmotivated to do writing for myself. At the moment, I am on leave for the Easter break. I took a little bit of rest and grasped some inspiration to write an article about tooth health. Check it out here: </p><ul><li><a href="/science/health-and-minerals/hydroxyapatite">All stuff hydroxyapatite and tooth health</a></li></ul>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Date night at Manjits]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2024/July /manjits_corrimal</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2024/July /manjits_corrimal</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[For dinner tonight, Nick made a reservation at Majits in Corrimal for 7 pm. Manjits is an Indian restaurant. It is very popular and almost everyone in the Illawarra knows of it. We often order from Manjits using Uber Eats. We have only dined here once before, in September last year.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For dinner tonight, Nick made a reservation at Majits in Corrimal for 7 pm. Manjits is an Indian restaurant. It is very popular and almost everyone in the Illawarra knows of it. We often order from Manjits using Uber Eats. We have only dined here once before, in September last year. </p><p>As Majits is a BYO restaurant, we took one of our New Zealand Syrah's with us that we got from Te Mata Estate in Hawke's Bay. They charge a $5 corking fee which is silly to be honest, as we pour the wine ourselves. But it works out to be a lot cheaper than ordering wines/beers at the restaurant. I also think it's a better option for us because our wines are probably much nicer than any of the one's they serve at the restaurant. </p><p>When we arrived, the restaurant was very empty. We sat on the balcony, and there was probably 5 other tables occupied. However, considering that this restaurant is very large, it felt very empty.</p><p>Nick opened the wine to allow it to oxidise a little before we drank. The first sip was amazing! I was feeling a bit of regret that we opened this bottle tonight. My eyes watered at the amazing taste of the wine. It was so flavoursome with a full body. Even with the crazy spices of the Indian, it never overpowered the wine. <em>Side note: looking online, these bottles are $30 NZD. However, they do not ship to Australia ☹️</em></p><p>As we sipped our wine and read through the menu, we were trying to remember the things that we ordered last time we were here (because they don't offer everything through Uber Eats). As I looked through my photos, I found a picture of the Samosa Chat that we ordered last year. I remember it being so delicious! Therefore, we ordered it again for an entre. On the menu, it says that the Samosa Chat comes in 2 pieces. We were tempted to get 2 but we stuck with only 1. This was a good decision as the serving was quite large. If we ordered more than one entre, it would have filled our bellies so much! </p><p>For the mains, we ordered Malai Kofta and Palak Paneer, with a side of rice and naans - Garlic for me and Chilli for Nick. The palak paneer was a must. This is the meal that I always order and the meal that I love! We were a little unsure of the Malai Kofta but once we tried it, we were in awe of the flavours and textures. It was served in a butter-like sauce, similar to their butter chicken. This was too much food though and I could not finish my naan or the Palak Paneer. Nontheless, our bellies were very satisfied! </p><table><thead><tr><th align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/manjits-d514e353d704d71267d4793ab0d7ce46.jpeg" width="1280" height="284" class="img_ev3q"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="center"><em>Img caption: Our meals for the evening at Manjits</em></td></tr></tbody></table>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>food in Illawarra</category>
            <category>Indian food</category>
            <category>restaurants</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sourdough pastry]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2024/June/sourdough-pastry</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2024/June/sourdough-pastry</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[What can we do with sourdough discard? I would hate to waste my sourdough discards, which is why I have been searching for different things to do with it. Did you know that discard lasts for a few days in the fridge? This recipe uses a 2 day old discard.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What can we do with sourdough discard? I would hate to waste my sourdough discards, which is why I have been searching for different things to do with it. Did you know that discard lasts for a few days in the fridge? This recipe uses a 2 day old discard.</p><p>So today, I wanted to make some pastry with it. Beforehand, I did a quick search and found that pastry follows the same method as a regular pastry recipe, only that it uses less flour. I used my previously developed Pastry recipe as follows: </p><p>Makes 2 sheets of pastry</p><p><strong>Ingredients:</strong> <br>
225 g flour <br>
25 g butter<br>
1 tbsp olive oil<br>
1/2 tsp salt<br>
1/2 tsp garlic powder<br>
50-100 g of sourdough starter*<br></p><p><strong>Method (pastry):</strong> </p><ol><li>The butter was cut into small cubes (0.5 cmx0.5cm) </li><li>The butter and flour was rubbed together to make a crumbled flour</li><li>The oil was added and mixed in, then the flour was rubbed further</li><li>salts were mixed in</li><li>Starter was mixed in. </li><li>A small amount of water was added (just to make it come together)</li><li>Stretch and fold of the pastry several times</li><li>Moulded the pastry into a Dish, covered and placed in the fridge overnight.*</li></ol><p><strong>Filling:</strong>
1/2 brown onion <br>
1 garlic cloves<br>
1/4 cup cream<br>
60 g ricotta<br>
1/3 cup tasty cheese<br>
200 g button mushrooms, sliced<br>
2 handfulls of spinach<br>
1 tsp salt
1/2 tsp pepper</p><ol start="9"><li>Over medium heat, melt butter and fry onion and garlic until onion is translucent. </li><li>Add mushrooms and fry until they start to sweat. </li><li>Add spinach.</li><li>In a seperate bowl, combine the cheese and cream. Add the mushroom mixture and salt and pepper. </li><li>Pour mixture into the dish (pre-moulded with pastry)</li><li>Cover the top with the second layer of pastry. </li><li>Bake at 200 °C (fan forced) for 30 minutes. </li></ol><table><thead><tr><th align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/pastry-sourdough-77f1ec953be77e6b4deee82903f935d0.jpeg" width="1280" height="340" class="img_ev3q"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="center"><em>Img caption: The rolling out of one pastry (left), the filling of the pastry in the dish (middle) and the final product (right).</em></td></tr></tbody></table><p><strong>Notes about this recipe:</strong>
Note about the starter: This was a discard that I kept in the fridge for 2 days. I think it is safe to leave sourdough discard for 3 days in the fridge, so I wanted to use it before I needed to throw it away. </p><p>NOTE about the hydration: on the 26.06.24: before I added the starter, I added 1/2 cup of water (which I realised was a mistake therefore this recipe is tweaked). After I added the starter, it was very sticky! This was wrong, the consistency should be crumbly. Therefore, it is crucial to add the sourdough starter before extra water, so you correct the consistency. </p><p>Note for step 8: Refrigeration is important for pastry. The colder it is, the better. You want the butter and oil to solidify to bring the crumbly consistency to your pastry. I also think that it will aid in bring flavours out of the sourdough.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>cooking</category>
            <category>my vegetarian cookbook</category>
            <category>sourdough starter</category>
            <category>sourdough discard</category>
            <category>pancakes</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sourdough Pancakes]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2024/June/sourdough-pancakes</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2024/June/sourdough-pancakes</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[On 23.6.24, I used my sourdough discard for the first time. At this point it was 10 days old. Just before I was preparing to use it, I noticed that it had rose almost double its initial size. It was very gaseous and therefore, I thought it was active and ready.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On 23.6.24, I used my sourdough discard for the first time. At this point it was 10 days old. Just before I was preparing to use it, I noticed that it had rose almost double its initial size. It was very gaseous and therefore, I thought it was active and ready. </p><p>The first recipe I used was the following:
Makes 5 pancakes. Serving size is probably 1-2. </p><p><strong>Ingredients:</strong>
97 g starter (discard)<br>
112 g plain flour<br>
1 tsp sugar<br>
1/2 tsp salt<br>
2 tsp baking powder<br>
3/4 cup of milk (warmed)<br>
1/2 frozen banana<br>
1 egg. <br></p><p><strong>Method:</strong></p><ol><li>Combine dry ingredients</li><li>Add wet ingredients</li><li>Let it sit for 5 minutes (it will bubble a bit because of the sourdough discard)</li><li>Fry 30 sec each side. </li><li>Serve with butter</li></ol><p>The pancakes were indeed very fluffy and full! I enjoyed these pancakes so much that a few days later, on 25.6.24, I made more! </p><p>The next time I made them, I changed the ingredients as follows (methods are the same): </p><p>50-100 g starter<br>
112 g plain flour <br>
1 scoop of protein powder<br>
1/2 tsp salt<br>
2 tsp baking powder<br>
3/4 cup milk (warmed)<br>
1/2 frozen banana<br>
1 egg. <br></p><p>These pancakes were delicious and I ate two for lunch the following day! </p><table><thead><tr><th align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/pancakes-40fb114e4f68df91687fbbf394ed3f36.jpeg" width="1280" height="359" class="img_ev3q"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="center"><em>Img caption: The batter (left image), pancakes cooking (middle image) and the final product (right image)</em></td></tr></tbody></table>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>cooking</category>
            <category>my vegetarian cookbook</category>
            <category>sourdough starter</category>
            <category>sourdough discard</category>
            <category>pancakes</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PhD examination]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2024/05/28/2024/May/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2024/05/28/2024/May/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[*Date created: 28.05.24,]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Date created: 28.05.24,
Date modified: 17.06.24</em> </p><p><em>Date: 28.05.24</em> <br>
What's new in the life of Carly? Recently I started working as a laboratory technician for ANFF (<a href="https://anff.org.au" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Australian National Fabrication Facility</a>), back at the Innovation Campus in Wollongong. ANFF is a government funded organisation that is designed to support Research and Development. There are several nodes located around Australia, with several in each state. The ANFF Materials node is located here at the University of Wollongong as well as the University of Newcastle, specialising in polymers, bioinks, and electromaterials.</p><p>I have been here for 2 weeks so far. At the moment, the work is pretty slow, yet I am trying to keep busy. I have been trained on the <a href="/blog/2024/May/icp_">ICP</a> and elemental analyser and am waiting for traiing by Greg on the digestor in order to further my training on the ICP. I hope to use it a few times in order to become more familiar since I am now the official trainer for it. While I wait for things to happen here, I have continued my learning with python. In fact, today I wrote a program with the following purposes: </p><ol><li>To create a new folder with the month, then a folder with the date</li><li>To take a file and convert it from txt to csv</li><li>To extract the X and Y values from the folder and normalise the Y column. </li><li>To create a line graph of the X and normalised Y values. </li><li>To export the image as a png with the date and activity as the file name. </li></ol><p>I feel as excited about programing as I did with the synthesis of my polymers. Both of these skills have different thresholds and I think they can complement each other very nicely. I just wish I could get a mixture of lab work and desk work... As I was told today "This place is very slow, as there are many changes happening.."</p><p>In addition, I have been learning a bi¬t of LaTeX. It was a large hurdle and a little traumatic installing it, only for Nick to point out to me later on that Typst (which I am more fluent with) is open access for offline use (something I did not realise before). Therefore, I looked through the extensions of VSCode and found the typst extension, which I immediately installed. I began to create a template for my publications, which is much nicer than using microsoft word!!!! If I could do one thing over again, it would be to use typst for my thesis. I will definitely be using this to create reports in the future. </p><p>In other news, both of the examiners have returned my PhD thesis. I am yet to receive it, however, my supervisors have told me that there are mostly minor corrections (They didn't want to give me too much information, and later I learned that they are not allowed to tell me anything). I'm hoping that I can correct it soon, but I am very nervous about what it will say! </p><div align="center"><table><thead><tr><th align="center"><img loading="lazy" alt="phd revision" src="/assets/images/phd-revision-2c8dffaf22a0504d3a2f184d98aba560.PNG" width="517" height="265" class="img_ev3q"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="center"><em>Caption: The only information I can get about my thesis at this point</em></td></tr></tbody></table></div><p><em>Date: 13.06.24</em> <br>
On Friday, 7 June 2024 at 8:57 AM, I received an email from the Graduate Research School with my thesis examination. My PhD will be awarded, pending minor changes to the thesis. This is probably the best result that I could hope for.</p><p>As I read the examiners reports, I was at first shocked and overwhelmed by the reports, however, as I read on, I realised that it was very positive, with only grammatical errors and mistakes. I ended up fixing my thesis within a day. </p><p>One of my reviewers said "The number of experiments performed was really impressive, even if part of them were unsuccessful and did not lead to the desired product." The other said "In summary, this is an excellent thesis and I recommend that the candidate be awarded a PhD degree." This made me feel really good about it. While I didn't get a commended thesis, I am glad that the reviews were positive. </p><p><em>Date: 17.06.24</em> <br>
On Thursday 13 June 2024, I met with my PhD supervisors and discussed my thesis. They were happy with the changes that I made and gave me a few additional suggestions. The next day, I sent an email to the head of postgraduate studies asking if he was happy with my corrections. After consulting with my supervisors, he then sent an email to the graduate research school approving my final submission. At 10:15 am today, I submitted the final version of my thesis!!! I am proud of the work I did and while I haven't published any manuscripts (yet hopefully), I believe I added something novel to the literature.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>PhD</category>
            <category>work</category>
            <category>thesis corrections</category>
            <category>python</category>
            <category>programming</category>
            <category>LaTeX</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Inductively Coupled Plasma (ICP) mass spectrometry (MS)/Optical emission spectroscopy (OES)]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2024/May/icp_</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2024/May/icp_</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Recently I started a position as a lab technician with Australian National Fabrication Facility (ANFF). One of the requirements of this position is to maintain the ICP (Fig 1). Therefore, I decided to write a short post here about ICP, which I will update with the various things that I have learned along the way.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Recently I started a position as a lab technician with Australian National Fabrication Facility (ANFF). One of the requirements of this position is to maintain the ICP (Fig 1). Therefore, I decided to write a short post here about ICP, which I will update with the various things that I have learned along the way. </p><table><thead><tr><th align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/icp-fig-2-03dffa70c83f6fd9a547e4522d46aa62.jpg" width="4713" height="2884" class="img_ev3q"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="center"><em>Fig 1. The ICP in my lab at the University of Wollongong, with the labelled components</em></td></tr></tbody></table><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-is-icp">What is ICP?<a href="#what-is-icp" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What is ICP?" title="Direct link to What is ICP?">​</a></h2><p>Inductively coupled plasma (ICP) mass spectrometry (MS) or optical emission spectroscopy (OES) is a method of elemental analysis which utilises a plasma source. In ICP-MS, the ions are directly measured. In contract, ICP-OES uses an optical spectrometer to measure the photons emitted as they pass through the plasma. While both methods are extremely fast to use, cheap and straightforward, the ICP-OES has a higher sensitivity to detection. </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="how-does-icp-work">How does ICP work?<a href="#how-does-icp-work" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to How does ICP work?" title="Direct link to How does ICP work?">​</a></h2><table><thead><tr><th align="center"><img loading="lazy" alt="Schematic of ICP" src="/assets/images/fig1-icp-b973c0fd8a33d264862421400b87c4e1.jpeg" width="1280" height="462" class="img_ev3q"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="center"><em>Figure 2. Schematic of ICP: (a) engineered setup and (b) behaviour of the sample inside the sample channel. Images taken from (Hou and Jones) and (McCurdy and Potter)</em></td></tr></tbody></table><p>A schematic of an ICP is displayed in Fig 2. The liquid sample is injected into a spray chamber which is converted to an aerosol via a nebuliser. During this process, only the very fine particles are injected into the inductor. In the inductor, the sample aerosol is further dried and vapourised due to the high temperatures (10000 K) in the sample carrier. In this process, all chemical bonds are broken, allowing for the vapourisation of each individual atom (Fig 2b). The free atoms collide with plasma, allowing them to transition to an excited state. Upon relaxation to ground state, the ions/atoms will emit a photon of characteristic energies, which can be used to determine the elemental origin of the ions. The total number of photons emitted is proportional to the concentration.</p><p>The ionisation plasma is typically argon gas as it is chemically inert and contains a high proportion of cations and electrons with a high electron density. In the set up shown in Fig 2a, radiofrequency (RF) is applied to a coil which produces “seed” electrons which are accelerated and collide with argon gas to form argon plasma and electrons:</p><p align="center"> Ar(g) → Ar<sup>+</sup> + e<sup>-</sup> </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="about-sample-preparation">About sample preparation<a href="#about-sample-preparation" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to About sample preparation" title="Direct link to About sample preparation">​</a></h2><p>Solubilised solutions (aqueous or organic) are required to perform ICP analysis. Therefore, samples (&lt;0.2 %&gt;) are typically treated with nitric acid (HNO<sub>3</sub>) or HCl, in a process referred to as "acid digestion".  Sample concentrations of &lt;0.2% are crucial to avoid any matrix effects.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="matrix-effects">Matrix effects<a href="#matrix-effects" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Matrix effects" title="Direct link to Matrix effects">​</a></h2><p>Matrix effects are interferences in the analysis due ton signal dift caused by the deposition of solids on the sample apertures or signal suppression caused by salt ions. The typical salt interference is caused by oxide formation, which seems to reduce the ion flow and promotes clogging at the sample cone (the interface that analyses ion extraction). With years of research, matrix effects have typically solved through the use of OES compared to MS. ICP-OES relies on photon emission rather than ion acceleration, which makes it less susceptible to interferences. </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="advantages-of-icp-compared-to-other-elemental-analyses">Advantages of ICP compared to other elemental analyses<a href="#advantages-of-icp-compared-to-other-elemental-analyses" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Advantages of ICP compared to other elemental analyses" title="Direct link to Advantages of ICP compared to other elemental analyses">​</a></h2><p>As ICP heats to very high temperatures, samples undergo more efficient vaporisation, atomisation and excitation. This allows for a wider range of elements to be analysed by ICP. In addition, the high temperature means that there is less water vapour present, in turn reducing the concentration of oxygen species and thus a lower level of matrix interferences caused by oxide formation. </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="references">References<a href="#references" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to References" title="Direct link to References">​</a></h2><ol><li>Ammann, A.A., Inductively coupled plasma mass spectrometry (ICP MS): a versatile tool. Journal of Mass Spectrometry, 2007. 42(4): p. 419-427.<br></li><li>Hou, X. and B.T. Jones, Inductively Coupled Plasma Optical Emission Spectrometry, in Encyclopedia of Analytical Chemistry. 2000, John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd: Chichester. p. 9468-6485.<br></li><li>McCurdy, E. and D. Potter, Optimising ICP-MS for the determination of trace metals in high matrix samples. Spectroscopy Europe, 2001. 13: p. 14+16-20.<br></li><li>Kopru, S. and M. Soylak, Inductively coupled plasma-mass spectrometry (ICP-MS) detection of trace metal contents of children cosmetics. Optical and Quantum Electronics, 2024. 56(3): p. 399.</li></ol>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Almost there]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/12/15/2023-12/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/12/15/2023-12/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[It's been just over a month since I've wrote something in my blog.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It's been just over a month since I've wrote something in my blog. </p><p>For the last month and a half, I have been working through the comments that I received back. It's been a real tough time, because there were a lot of comments. I honestly felt like everything I knew about my topic was wrong. I have been reading so much and redoing all my figures/analyses. Each day, I started work at 7 am and continued until 10 pm. I even spent all my weekends working on it. Until finally, I felt proud of my thesis! Now, it is being reviewed by one of my supervisors. </p><p>The plan now is to write a couple of research papers. However, my current dilemma is that I dont want to write a paper if my supervisors do not agree with what I wrote in my thesis.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>PhD</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Updates]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/10/31/2023-10/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/10/31/2023-10/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Over the weekend, Nick and I headed to the Hunter Valley for a wedding. It was great to get away, and now I am feeling fresh to resume writing.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over the weekend, Nick and I headed to the <a href="/life/trips/hunter-valley">Hunter Valley</a> for a wedding. It was great to get away, and now I am feeling fresh to resume writing.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PhD update]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/10/25/2023-10/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/10/25/2023-10/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[- [x] As it stands, I have completed writing my PhD thesis. Below is a table summary of the chapters, with type of chapter, number of words (in total, incl. references, and figures) and number of pages]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul class="contains-task-list containsTaskList_mC6p"><li class="task-list-item"><input type="checkbox" checked="" disabled=""> <!-- -->As it stands, I have completed writing my PhD thesis. Below is a table summary of the chapters, with type of chapter, number of words (in total, incl. references, and figures) and number of pages</li><li class="task-list-item"><input type="checkbox" disabled=""> <!-- -->I still have a few more experiments to conduct for Research Chapter 5 and 7. </li><li class="task-list-item"><input type="checkbox" disabled=""> <!-- -->I still need to write up the supporting information (which will be a lot)</li><li class="task-list-item"><input type="checkbox" disabled=""> <!-- -->I still need to write papers. </li><li class="task-list-item"><input type="checkbox" disabled=""> <!-- -->I plan to complete my thesis and send by Friday 27 Oct. </li></ul><h5 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="table-summary-of-my-phd-thesis">Table Summary of my PhD thesis:<a href="#table-summary-of-my-phd-thesis" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Table Summary of my PhD thesis:" title="Direct link to Table Summary of my PhD thesis:">​</a></h5><table><thead><tr><th align="left">Chapter</th><th align="center">Content</th><th align="center">Words</th><th align="right">Pages</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left">1</td><td align="center">Intro</td><td align="center">11937</td><td align="right">36</td></tr><tr><td align="left">2</td><td align="center">Methods</td><td align="center">9150</td><td align="right">27</td></tr><tr><td align="left">3</td><td align="center">Research</td><td align="center">6289</td><td align="right">29</td></tr><tr><td align="left">4</td><td align="center">Research</td><td align="center">11257</td><td align="right">39</td></tr><tr><td align="left">5</td><td align="center">Research</td><td align="center">6351</td><td align="right">27</td></tr><tr><td align="left">6</td><td align="center">Research</td><td align="center">6887</td><td align="right">24</td></tr><tr><td align="left">7</td><td align="center">Research</td><td align="center">9908</td><td align="right">34</td></tr><tr><td align="left">8</td><td align="center">Conclusions</td><td align="center">3700</td><td align="right">11</td></tr><tr><td align="left">Total</td><td align="center"></td><td align="center">65479</td><td align="right">227</td></tr></tbody></table>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[More content]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/10/22/2023-10/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/10/22/2023-10/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A few updates include:]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A few updates include: </p><ul><li><a href="/phd/tips-for-writing">Tips for writing</a> in PhD section</li><li><a href="/life/surf-lifesaving/patrol-days">Recap of patrol</a> in Life section / Surf Lifesaving</li><li><a href="/phd/pros-cons">Pros and cons for starting a PhD</a> in PhD section</li><li>Added <a href="/life/food-and-drink/restaurants-and-bars/rocksalt-menai">Rock Salt, Menai</a> to Life section / Food and drink / Restaurants and bars</li><li>Added <a href="/life/trips/hunter-valley">Trips to the Hunter Valley</a> to Life section / Trips</li></ul>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Another Saturday]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/10/21/2023-10/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/10/21/2023-10/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Updates:]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Updates:</p><ol><li><a href="/phd/starting-over-a-phd">If I could start my PhD again</a></li></ol>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Some days are productive, some days are not]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/08/25/2023-08/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/08/25/2023-08/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Last Thursday, my supervisor cancelled my weekly PhD meeting and instead requested that we sit down and go through my thesis and decide what we need to do moving forward. Both Pawel and David agreed that I should not be doing anymore lab work and just focus on writing my thesis! There it is "only focus on writing".]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last Thursday, my supervisor cancelled my weekly PhD meeting and instead requested that we sit down and go through my thesis and decide what we need to do moving forward. Both Pawel and David agreed that I should not be doing anymore lab work and just focus on writing my thesis! There it is "only focus on writing". </p><p><em>Productivity:</em> From Friday onwards, I started writing all my results down. I wrote a lot in the span of 4 days and I felt that if I kept writing then I could be finished by the end of the month. </p><p><em>Unproductive:</em> On Wednesday 23 August, I had a really bad day of writing. By 3 pm, I was on the lounge watching a TV show. I did not attempt to recommence writing for the rest of the evening. It really messed me around on Thursday. At this rate, I won't finish my PhD in time!</p><p><em>A tip to improve productivity:</em> I was lucky this week in my Thursday meeting. I got a few tips from my supervisors about writing. David commented that the best thing to do when you are not feeling like thinking is to write out the methods chapter. He was right. Writing out my methods chapter is a simple way to get myself in the mood of writing and to continue my writing routine. </p><p><em>More unproductivity:</em> This morning, I went driving around Wollongong to try and get a quote to fix my passenger-side mirror of my car. Grant from Fernhill Smash Repairs told me that he would be in touch later in the afternoon. NOTE: the passenger side-mirror is no longer afixed to the car as I nipped it off on the way home from the beach yesterday. Without a passenger side-mirror, I cannot drive my car. This means that I can't drive to North Wollongong beach! I need to paddle in the morning for me to feel fresh for a day of writing! This screwed up my whole day. At 10 am, I gave up on writing and decided to head to Innovation Campus to get some data off the computers. I ran there and remained until 4 pm..... and that is all I did today.</p><p>In the evening, Nick and I walked to <a href="/life/food-and-drink/craft-beer/illawarra/barrel-shephard">The Barrel Shephard</a> for dinner and drinks. I felt aweful, like I didn't deserve to be going out after a day of very little work and progress. Note to future self: stop going into the lab, save it for the weekend or afternoons.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A very stupid thing]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/08/08/2023-08/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/08/08/2023-08/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[When I woke up at 5.55 am, it seemed like it was going to be another cracker of a day. I prepared for teaching, went for a run, did some stretching and showered all before 8.30 am. I was more than ready to make huge progress today!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When I woke up at 5.55 am, it seemed like it was going to be another cracker of a day. I prepared for teaching, went for a run, did some stretching and showered all before 8.30 am. I was more than ready to make huge progress today! </p><p>I arrived at work at 9 am and from the minute I began to do things in the lab, everything went wrong. I couldn't get any good data. Around 10 am, I went to get help to fix a cable for my potentiostat (as the wires lost connection to reduce the signal). However, I was unsuccessful in getting help. A colleague/researcher said to meet her at 3 pm to repair the cable; but I couldnt wait this long as I was due to teach at 1.30 til 4.30 pm (Week 3 of Semester 2).. </p><p>By this point it was 11 am - I was feeling really tired and unmotivated. </p><p>My first thought was to go home. I lost motivation when I realised that I would only be home for 1 hour before having to leave again. Instead, I pulled out my soft back warmer from my draw and used it as a pillow. I put my head down on the desk and had an hour nap. </p><p>I woke up less tired than before, but really groggy. I packed my safety glasses and water bottle into my handbag and walked towards my car, then drove to the main campus. Travel between the innovation campus and the main campus is really tedious and it is often difficult to find parking in the middle of the day. </p><p>I was parked and ready to get out of the car at 1 pm. I walked towards Panzinis, a cafe located in front of the UOW library. I go here for coffee because they offer staff discounts and I love discouts! I ordered my coffee and it was made within 5 minutes. It was a rather pleasant experience - too bad that I was not in a good mood. </p><p>The undergraduate chemistry labs are located in building 21 on level 3. I headed here after I was handed my coffee - but I was at least 20 minutes early. When I walked into the lab, it was empty abar one demonstrator - Sue. I chatted for less than a minute before rereading over my emails that said I was only rostered for Week 9. In sheer disbelief, I spent a few minutes researching my emails and was convinced that I showed up for no reason! In embarrassment, I left and drove to North Wollongong beach. "Wow" I thought. "How stupid". "Why didn't I read my emails?" </p><p>I was pretty relieved though, because I didn't really want to teach. I don't need the extra funds that bad and it's not worth taking time away from my writing. Excited that I could fix the potentiostat, I also sent an email to a colleague, indicating my error and that I would be there at 3 pm. </p><p>Just as I was about to get out of my car and go for a dip in the ocean to calm down my anxiety and embarrassment, I received an email from Giel (the subject coordinator) who asked me to come back because I was rostered to work. Can you believe how embarrassed I was after this? It took me 15 minutes to return, park and walk to the labs. I quickly walked into the service room, dodging the lines of students waiting to collect a pH probe for their experiment. I threw on a red lab coat, my safety glasses and grabbed a pen. </p><p>I apologised several times to Giel and I literally felt like slapping my forehead because it was such a stupid thing that happened. The worst thing though, was sending a third email to my colleague telling her that I was wrong and I was meant to teach! </p><p>The labs were very slow and very basic. The students were working on acid-base titrations. In that moment, I thought that it wasn't too bad. I actually enjoyed it.  I'm just glad that I don't have to teach all the time. The labs ended at 4.30 pm. I drove straight home and relaxed until dinner time. </p><p>I honestly feel like I wasted the whole day.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rewarding myself]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/08/04/2023-08/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/08/04/2023-08/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Lately, I have been freaking out with the amount of work still left in my PhD. Today, I had planned to have a writing day but I realised as I opened various thesis chapters, that I have actually written a lot! At 11 am, I decided to head into the lab to try to resynthesise a monomer for my second research chapter. While searching the freezer for my materials, I came across a molecule that I had synthesised previously, but never used. It was a dibromo-compound that was initially synthesised for a grignard reaction.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lately, I have been freaking out with the amount of work still left in my PhD. Today, I had planned to have a writing day but I realised as I opened various thesis chapters, that I have actually written a lot! At 11 am, I decided to head into the lab to try to resynthesise a monomer for my second research chapter. While searching the freezer for my materials, I came across a molecule that I had synthesised previously, but never used. It was a dibromo-compound that was initially synthesised for a grignard reaction. </p><p>For fun, I set up a 1 mL (200 mg) scale <a href="/science/polymer-science/synthesis/darp">direct arylation polymerisation</a>. For the rest of the day, I felt so happy and accomplished. I feel so excited to work this polymer up and characterise it. </p><p>To hear more about this, and see the fun I have with these reactions, visit <a href="/phd/side-projects">side projects</a>. </p><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/dhap-461e005e73beee5a4a5377372feae3c5.jpeg" width="60%" class="centered-image img_ev3q">]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Garlic & Rosemary Pull apart bread]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/08/02/2023-08/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/08/02/2023-08/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[It's already August! Wow, where has the time gone? Five months left until I need to submit my PhD thesis.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It's already August! Wow, where has the time gone? Five months left until I need to submit my PhD thesis. </p><p>I arrived home from work after an unsuccessful day in the lab. The electrodes attached to my potentiostat were disfunctioning. I spent my 3 hours of lab time, trying to trouble shoot the problem. With the help of one of the guys in the workshop, I was able to fix the electrode. However, upon a "dummy test", the signal was not strong. I gave up, and decided to go home and not waste anymore time. </p><p>I arrived home and prepared a quiche for dinner. I was feeling inspired by Emma (as over the weekend, she made a really awesome scrambled eggs). The egg filling alone contained some butter and rosemary. </p><p>After I finished preparing dinner, I was still in the mood to cook - anything to avoid working on my thesis! I decided to prepare tomorrow nights dinner as well. </p><p>I don't know about you, but I get tired of eating similar things all the time. I feel like it is super boring and not creative at all. While I was having these thoughts, I had finished the rest of our loaf of bread. That's when I was inspired to make some bread. </p><p>I remember when I was much younger, around 15 years old and would often bake various things for my family. I enjoyed baking a lot - from bread to cakes. However, I saw so many people around me who were a lot better. I often compared myself to others and it really demotivated me to cook (Yes, I always wanted to be the best). I wonder what life would have been like if I didn't compare myself and just did the things that I enjoyed - because I enjoyed them. </p><p>Maybe my enjoyment of baking and "creative cooking" is the reason that I chose chemistry. I always wonder what drove me to stay in chemistry. I usually say that it was because I got the best marks for the least amount of effort - which is probably true. Now, I am thinking that it was also because I was using my hands to create something. Synthesis is very similar to cooking: a step by step process to create something wonderful. </p><p>The funny thing is though, I struggle so much to follow recipes. The same thing applies in the lab: I struggle a lot to follow new synthetic protocols. This caused so much stress during my undergrad: as I didn't perform as well as some of the other students. Somehow I have made it through and am almost finished a PhD in chemistry! Sometimes I forget how amazing it is that I've made it this far. Dani had to remind me earlier today when we were discussing my PhD. </p><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/garlic-rosemary-bread-22e55f4fb8219f5ec83cee62fce49026.jpeg" width="50%" class="centered-image img_ev3q">]]></content:encoded>
            <category>cooking</category>
            <category>My vegetarian cookbook</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Changing my attitude]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/28/2023-07/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/28/2023-07/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[It didn't take long to change my attitude once I acknowledged it.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It didn't take long to change my attitude once I acknowledged it. </p><p>Over the last few days, I have had time to reflect on my actions and my feelings and I realised that I need to be kinder to myself and try to think of "criticism" as "feedback". My Supervisors have 50 years of experience over me, so I need to stop comparing myself to other people. Instead, I need to compare myself from the start of my PhD to myself now. I am very proud of how much I've grown as a person and a scientist. </p><p>My feelings of doom have become more optimistic as I feel excited to finish and get a job in the real world! It's funny how a little bit of perspective can make the world around you seem more positive. </p><p>This weekend, I am taking a break and we are heading up to Terrigal for Emma's 30th birthday and Hens weekend! Should be good.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Office critique]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/25/2023-07/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/25/2023-07/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Currently I am writing my thesis and subsequent manuscripts. I have so many emotions towards finishing my PhD.  At times I am really enjoying writing, and at other times I just want it all to finish. But the thought of finishing my PhD gives me a lot of anxiety, as this is all I've known for a long time. I fear that I will be terrible at any job I get in the future. Right now, I justify my work as "I am just a student", I am learning. What if, when I finish my PhD, I can't find anything that I am good at? What if I can't find a job that I like? This really scares me and I often worry about it.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Currently I am writing my thesis and subsequent manuscripts. I have so many emotions towards finishing my PhD.  At times I am really enjoying writing, and at other times I just want it all to finish. But the thought of finishing my PhD gives me a lot of anxiety, as this is all I've known for a long time. I fear that I will be terrible at any job I get in the future. Right now, I justify my work as "I am just a student", I am learning. What if, when I finish my PhD, I can't find anything that I am good at? What if I can't find a job that I like? This really scares me and I often worry about it. </p><p>At 9 am this morning, I had a meeting with my supervisors, to talk about my long awaited, first manuscript. We spoke about the structure and story of the research paper, and their feedback was very helpful. I'm kicking myself that I didn't show them sooner and push for this to be published 2 years ago (when the work was originally done).</p><p>During this meeting, I didn't realise that I was figgeting a lot. I was playing with my hair, biting my nails, moving around and just sitting very casually. Afterwards, it was pointed it out, and I was really embarrassed. I am glad that he said something to me though, because I feel like in future meetings I can pay closer attention to it. </p><p>In my defense though, my PhD feels very casual. I feel like my supervisors are my family; but maybe I am taking my comfort for granted. I also feel like it is not my work place. I am not treated like a staff member, nor do I get the same treatment as a staff member. </p><p>I went home after the meeting feeling really embarrased and a bit upset. To be honest, at the moment, I don't like certain things about myself; like my current connection with friends or my behaviour when I am stressed or anxious. I feel like I've spent a lot of time complaining about things and blaming others for my bad attitude. I need to retake control of my actions, stop complaining and just get stuff done. </p><p>I worked through comments for the rest of the day and then around 4 pm, I decided to go out for a run. Running has always helped me cope with my anxiety. I ran 10 km - which is the most I've ran since the marathon back in July 2022. My mood significantly improved since the run; however, not long after, I started to feel a bit sad. I want things to change. I want to be better.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Date night]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/23/2023-07/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/23/2023-07/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Last night, Nick and I went to the movies to watch Oppenheimer, followed by dinner at Din Tai Fung in Miranda. The movie was really good, it told the story of Robert J Oppenheimer, a theoretical phyicist who helped to build the atomic bomb. I read some other reviews online. They say that Christopher Nolan got a lot of the biography right, with only a little bit of dramatisation.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last night, Nick and I went to the movies to watch Oppenheimer, followed by dinner at Din Tai Fung in Miranda. The movie was really good, it told the story of Robert J Oppenheimer, a theoretical phyicist who helped to build the atomic bomb. I read some other reviews online. They say that Christopher Nolan got a lot of the biography right, with only a little bit of dramatisation. </p><p>We sat on the beds at the front of the cinema. It was so comfortable and I was so happy that we chose those seats because it was a 3 hour movie! The alternative seating would've been wildly uncomfortable. </p><p>Dinner afterwards was also really great. We had dumplings and steamed buns! Yummy. </p><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/dumplings-buns-3e28292d534284e77a7f98dc5ba26e79.jpeg" width="40%" class="centered-image img_ev3q">]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My shoulder]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/17/2023-07/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/17/2023-07/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[An update on my shoulder: On 31 May, I fell off my paddle board and hit the right side of my body on the ground (the waves were very dumping at NW beach). As a result, I could barely move my arm or shoulder. As of last week, my shoulder was not in good shape - even after 5 weeks! Last week, I went for an xray. The doctor says that there may be some form of a fracture in my scapula bone. She requested that I get a CT scan. The CT scan confirmed that I have a fracture of the acromion. To my luck though, it is not located in the joint, nor does it affect the joint. Now it's just a waiting game to heal.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An update on my shoulder: On 31 May, I fell off my paddle board and hit the right side of my body on the ground (the waves were very dumping at NW beach). As a result, I could barely move my arm or shoulder. As of last week, my shoulder was not in good shape - even after 5 weeks! Last week, I went for an xray. The doctor says that there may be some form of a fracture in my scapula bone. She requested that I get a CT scan. The CT scan confirmed that I have a fracture of the acromion. To my luck though, it is not located in the joint, nor does it affect the joint. Now it's just a waiting game to heal.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[History of carly.cool]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/06/2023-07/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/07/06/2023-07/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[We are live with the new website!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We are live with the new website! </p><p>Let's not forget how the homepage looked just yesterday!</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="The first homepage of carly.cool" src="/assets/images/version1-website-701117e0af7c74607570009258cf9c9b.png" width="1418" height="1253" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Website!]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/new-website</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/new-website</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Now, Carly.cool runs using Docusaurus.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Now, Carly.cool runs using Docusaurus.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Roosters vs. Raiders NRL game]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/06/25/2023-06/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/06/25/2023-06/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[football]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" alt="football" src="/assets/images/food-football-bde9470f49847f8ce4e5303100d15759.png" width="2044" height="939" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Roosters vs. Raiders game. Nick's dad had 4 spare corporate box tickets. Nick invited Nathan and Emma to come with us.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Back to reality]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/06/26/2023-06/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/06/26/2023-06/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[chip on a beenbag]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" alt="chip on a beenbag" src="/assets/images/chip-on-beenbag-2a02c87067f687f6c010ca68a6bbcdb7.png" width="3419" height="1475" class="img_ev3q">
Standard Monday workday. I feel too tired to go to the lab. I decided to work from home. All day, I have not done any thesis writing for my PhD , only updating my blog. I feel very nervous to go into the lab tomorrow. My supervisors want me to go to NZLD to do some lab work. After my trip to <a href="/life/trips/usa">USA 2023</a>, I don't want to go anywhere for the rest of the year. It is too windy to do any outside activities but I am feeling stressed from my lack of water time - swimming or paddling.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zayne's 1st birthday & Baptism]]></title>
            <link>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/06/24/2023-06/</link>
            <guid>https://coolcarly.github.io/blog/2023/06/24/2023-06/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[On this day, I arrived home from USA and headed straight to mum's to get ready for Zayne's First Birthday and Baptism.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On this day, I arrived home from <a href="/life/trips/usa">USA</a> and headed straight to mum's to get ready for <a href="/life/events/2023/zayne-bday-1">Zayne's First Birthday and Baptism</a>. </p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Zayne" src="/assets/images/zayne1-2fa02b8a2368813f24431c87668e431f.png" width="3130" height="1297" class="img_ev3q">
Zayne, my littlest love.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>